[
  {
    "question": "which of these names did not reflect in the book of Genesis?",
    "answers": "Enoch, Ham, Elizabeth",
    "correct_answer": "Elizabeth",
    "book_of_bible": "Genesis"
  },
  {
    "question": "which of these events is not recorded in the book of Genesis?",
    "answers": "Tower of Babel, The Birth of Moses, The ark",
    "correct_answer": "The Birth of Moses",
    "book_of_bible": "Genesis"
  },
  {
    "question": "Noah is not the father of one of these men?",
    "answers": "Uz, Sham, Ham",
    "correct_answer": "Uz",
    "book_of_bible": "Genesis"
  },
  {
    "question": "Eve gave birth to the following except?",
    "answers": "Seth, Cain, Nimrod",
    "correct_answer": "Nimrod",
    "book_of_bible": "Genesis"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Genesis, God placed a curse on Adam, Eve and .............?",
    "answers": "The water, Adam\u2019s friend, The serpent",
    "correct_answer": "Nimrod",
    "book_of_bible": "Genesis"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Genesis, the following were cursed, except\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026?",
    "answers": "Cain, Ham, Nahor",
    "correct_answer": "Nahor",
    "book_of_bible": "Genesis"
  },
  {
    "question": "one of these men walked with God intimately?",
    "answers": "Enoch, Seth, Ishmeal",
    "correct_answer": "Enoch",
    "book_of_bible": "Genesis"
  },
  {
    "question": "............is the father of Noah?",
    "answers": "Lamech, Abraham, Jonah",
    "correct_answer": "Lamech",
    "book_of_bible": "Genesis"
  },
  {
    "question": "............... is the oldest man that ever lived on earth?",
    "answers": "Adam, Elijah, Methuselah",
    "correct_answer": "Methuselah",
    "book_of_bible": "Genesis"
  },
  {
    "question": "which of the options below makes up the first book of the Bible \"Ge\u2026\u2026\u2026\u2026.is\"?",
    "answers": "Nes, esn, ens",
    "correct_answer": "nes",
    "book_of_bible": "Genesis"
  },
  {
    "question": "what was the first assignment that Adam carried out in the garden?",
    "answers": "Naming of creatures, Dressing the Garden, ate the forbidden fruits",
    "correct_answer": "Naming of creatures",
    "book_of_bible": "Genesis"
  },
  {
    "question": "what event in Genesis lead to the multiplicity of languages?",
    "answers": "The building of the tower of Babel, The murder of Abel, The great flood",
    "correct_answer": "The building of the tower of Babel",
    "book_of_bible": "Genesis"
  },
  {
    "question": "Exodus is the ............... of the Bible ?",
    "answers": "5th book of the Bible, 2nd book of the Bible, 1st book of the Bible",
    "correct_answer": "2nd book of the Bible",
    "book_of_bible": "Exodus"
  },
  {
    "question": "the following are key players in the book of Exodus except............?",
    "answers": "Moses, Jethro, Rehab",
    "correct_answer": "Rehab",
    "book_of_bible": "Exodus"
  },
  {
    "question": "................... can be regarded as the number two after Moses ?",
    "answers": "Caleb, Aaron, Jethro",
    "correct_answer": "Aaron",
    "book_of_bible": "Exodus"
  },
  {
    "question": "................... acted as Moses\u2019s spoke man in Egypt?",
    "answers": "Aaron, Joshua, Caleb",
    "correct_answer": "Aaron",
    "book_of_bible": "Exodus"
  },
  {
    "question": "what action distinguished Joshua and Caleb from the other spies?",
    "answers": "The brought good report, They were Moses\u2019 blood relations, God\u2019s favor",
    "correct_answer": "The brought good report",
    "book_of_bible": "Exodus"
  },
  {
    "question": "what is the name of Moses\u2019 father - in law?",
    "answers": "Jethro, Abimelech, Josiah",
    "correct_answer": "Jethro",
    "book_of_bible": "Exodus"
  },
  {
    "question": "what is the name of the wife of Moses?",
    "answers": "Zipporah, Bilhah, Leah",
    "correct_answer": "Zipporah",
    "book_of_bible": "Exodus"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many children does Moses have?",
    "answers": "9, None, 2",
    "correct_answer": "2",
    "book_of_bible": "Exodus"
  },
  {
    "question": "................... is a brother of Moses Son?",
    "answers": "Reuben, Joshua, Aaron",
    "correct_answer": "Aaron",
    "book_of_bible": "Exodus"
  },
  {
    "question": "who is the father of Zipporah?",
    "answers": "Jacob,  Jethro, Joseph",
    "correct_answer": "Jethro",
    "book_of_bible": "Exodus"
  },
  {
    "question": "which of these books comes before the book of numbers?",
    "answers": "Genesis, Joshua, Leviticus",
    "correct_answer": "Leviticus",
    "book_of_bible": "Leviticus"
  },
  {
    "question": "the book of Leviticus centers on all of the following except............... ?",
    "answers": "Priestly duties, Offerings, The reign of King Joseph",
    "correct_answer": "The reign of King Joseph",
    "book_of_bible": "Leviticus"
  },
  {
    "question": "Aaron served as ...................... before Israel ?",
    "answers": "War Commander, High priest, Moses\u2019 Personal Assistant",
    "correct_answer": "High priest",
    "book_of_bible": "Leviticus"
  },
  {
    "question": "aside from the 10 commandments, what other information did Moses received from God?",
    "answers": "set of instructions on how to build the Tabernacle, Nothing more, The rod",
    "correct_answer": "set of instructions on how to build the Tabernacle",
    "book_of_bible": "Leviticus"
  },
  {
    "question": "What judgement came upon Nadab and Abihu for offering an unacceptable offering?",
    "answers": "Lion ate them, they were consumed by fire, They were stone to death",
    "correct_answer": "they were consumed by fire",
    "book_of_bible": "Leviticus"
  },
  {
    "question": "for an offering to be acceptable, it must be ................. ?",
    "answers": "Blemish, Big, Timely",
    "correct_answer": "Blemish",
    "book_of_bible": "Leviticus"
  },
  {
    "question": "one of the following type of offerings was recorded in the book Leviticus?",
    "answers": "Prophetic Offering, Holiness Offering, Sin Offering",
    "correct_answer": "Sin Offering",
    "book_of_bible": "Leviticus"
  },
  {
    "question": "what is the word used to describe an offering made by fire in the book of Leviticus?",
    "answers": "burnt offering, special offering, highest offering",
    "correct_answer": "burnt offering",
    "book_of_bible": "Leviticus"
  },
  {
    "question": "according to the book of Leviticus, a grain offering must be seasoned with ..................?",
    "answers": "Salt, Honey, Perfume",
    "correct_answer": "Salt",
    "book_of_bible": "Leviticus"
  },
  {
    "question": "the following were used as offerings in Leviticus, except............ ?",
    "answers": "Dove, Fish, Pigeon",
    "correct_answer": "Fish",
    "book_of_bible": "Leviticus"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was struck by God with leprosy for insulting Moses?",
    "answers": "Miriam, Lot\u2019s wife, Zipporah",
    "correct_answer": "Miriam",
    "book_of_bible": "Numbers"
  },
  {
    "question": "God spoke to Moses and ................ in Numbers 21?",
    "answers": "Aaron, Joshua, Moses only",
    "correct_answer": "Aaron",
    "book_of_bible": "Numbers"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who did God choose to be the captain for the house of Judah?",
    "answers": "Samson, Joshua, Nahshon",
    "correct_answer": "Nahshon",
    "book_of_bible": "Numbers"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these is the first son of Aaron?",
    "answers": "Nadab, Abihu, Ithamar",
    "correct_answer": "Nadab",
    "book_of_bible": "Numbers"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these tribe did God instruct Moses to present before Aaron in Numbers 36?",
    "answers": "Judah, Joseph, Levi",
    "correct_answer": "Levi",
    "book_of_bible": "Numbers"
  },
  {
    "question": "The sons of Levi are Gershon, Kohath and ...................... ?",
    "answers": "Merari, Aaron, Eleazer",
    "correct_answer": "Merari",
    "book_of_bible": "Numbers"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tribe of Israel did God chose for himself as the firstborn?",
    "answers": "Judah, Levi, Reuben",
    "correct_answer": "Levi",
    "book_of_bible": "Numbers"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these groups of persons did God instructed the Israelites to put out of the camp?",
    "answers": "Strangers, Lepers, women",
    "correct_answer": "Lepers",
    "book_of_bible": "Numbers"
  },
  {
    "question": "which of these vows is considered a separation unto God?",
    "answers": "a vow of Nazarite, deep vow, a priestly vow",
    "correct_answer": "a vow of Nazarite",
    "book_of_bible": "Numbers"
  },
  {
    "question": "................... is the name given to the place where the fire of the Lord burnt some of the Israelites?",
    "answers": "Shiloh, Bethel, Taberah",
    "correct_answer": "Taberah",
    "book_of_bible": "Numbers"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who died at Mosera?",
    "answers": "Moses, The 2 spies, Aaron",
    "correct_answer": "Aaron",
    "book_of_bible": "Deuteronomy"
  },
  {
    "question": "What happens if a man has an affair with a married woman?",
    "book_of_bible": "deuteronomy",
    "answers": "they will both die, they should be forgiven, they must present an offering",
    "correct_answer": "they will both die"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Deuteronomy",
    "question": "Who does the \"secret things\" belong to?",
    "answers": "Moses, the high priest, the Lord",
    "correct_answer": "the Lord"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Deuteronomy",
    "question": "Which of these men died in Moab?",
    "answers": "Moses, Ithamar, Jethro",
    "correct_answer": "Moses"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Deuteronomy",
    "question": "from which of these mountains did Moses viewed the land of Canaan?",
    "answers": "Mount Nebo, Mount Oreb, Mount Olives",
    "correct_answer": "Mount Nebo"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Deuteronomy",
    "question": "how old was Moses when he died?",
    "answers": "99 years, 157 years, 120 years",
    "correct_answer": "120 years"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Deuteronomy",
    "question": "what book comes after numbers?",
    "answers": "Leviticus, Deuteronomy, Joshua",
    "correct_answer": "Deuteronomy"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Deuteronomy",
    "question": "who slew Sihon the king of the amorites?",
    "answers": "Moses, Miriam, Joshua",
    "correct_answer": "Moses"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Deuteronomy",
    "question": "one of the points raised in the negative report of the 10 spies, was that they saw \u2026\u2026\u2026.?",
    "answers": "the sons of Anakim, Goliath, Fire every where",
    "correct_answer": "the sons of Anakim"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Deuteronomy",
    "question": "who is the father of Joshua?",
    "answers": "Nun, Bethuel, Terah",
    "correct_answer": "Nun"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Deuteronomy",
    "question": "Who serve as a minister to Moses?",
    "answers": "The high priest, Joshua, Aaron",
    "correct_answer": "Joshua"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Joshua",
    "question": "\"...only be strong and be of a good courage\" who was this statement directed to?",
    "answers": "Joshua, Moses, Jacob",
    "correct_answer": "Joshua"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Joshua",
    "question": "from where did Joshua sent the spies to go and spy out the city of Jericho?",
    "answers": "Ai, Gath, Shittim",
    "correct_answer": "Shittim"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Joshua",
    "question": "who received and show great hospitality to the spies Joshua sent to Jericho?",
    "answers": "Rahab, Hannah, Esther",
    "correct_answer": "Rahab"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Joshua",
    "question": "which river did the Israelites cross over to possess the land of Jericho?",
    "answers": "the red sea, river nile, river Jordan",
    "correct_answer": "river Jordan"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Joshua",
    "question": "what is the name of the first place the Israelites occupied after they crossed river Jordan?",
    "answers": "Jericho, Sodom, Gilgal",
    "correct_answer": "Gilgal"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Joshua",
    "question": "What did God asked Joshua to do to the Children after they crossed the River Jordan?",
    "answers": "to circumcise them, to count them, to bless them",
    "correct_answer": "to circumcise them"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Joshua",
    "question": "how many times in total did the Israelites marched round the walls of Jericho before it collapsed?",
    "answers": "13 times, 7 times, 10 times",
    "correct_answer": "10 times"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Joshua",
    "question": "which of these committed a trespass by stealing what is accursed?",
    "answers": "Achah,. Ammib, Omar",
    "correct_answer": "Carmi"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Joshua",
    "question": "which small nation defeated the Israelites in battle due to achan\u2019s sin?",
    "answers": "Jericho, Ai, Sodom",
    "correct_answer": "Ai"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Joshua",
    "question": "who committed the trespass that led to the defeat of Israel when they battled against Ai?",
    "answers": "Aaron, the men of Joshua, Achan",
    "correct_answer": "Achan"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Joshua",
    "question": "One of these men had his thumbs and great toes cut off when the tribe of Judah and Simeon battle against him?",
    "answers": "Abimelech, Adonibezek, Pharoah",
    "correct_answer": "Adonibezek"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Judges",
    "question": "which nation forced the tribe of Dan into the mountain?",
    "answers": "the hivites, the jebusites, the Amorites",
    "correct_answer": "the Amorites"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Judges",
    "question": "how old was Joshua when he died?",
    "answers": "430 years, 121 years, 110 years",
    "correct_answer": "110 years"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Judges",
    "question": "which of these Kings enslaved the Israelites for 8 years after the death of Joshua?",
    "answers": "King Chush, King Chushanrishathaim, King Og",
    "correct_answer": "King Chushanrishathaim"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Judges",
    "question": "who became the leader of the Israelites after the death of Joshua?",
    "answers": "Othniel, Aaron, Caleb",
    "correct_answer": "Othniel"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Judges",
    "question": "the Israelites were enslaved by King Eglon of Moab for how many years?",
    "answers": "18 years, 12 years, 9 years",
    "correct_answer": "18 years"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Judges",
    "question": "which of these Kings is described as a very fat man?",
    "answers": "King Eglon, King Og, King Balaam",
    "correct_answer": "King Eglon"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Judges",
    "question": "what is the name of the left-handed man that God raised to deliver Israel from the bondage of King Eglon?",
    "answers": "Ehud, Gideon, Samson",
    "correct_answer": "Ehud"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Judges",
    "question": "what did Ehud used to kill King Eglon?",
    "answers": "a spear, a gun, a double edge dagger",
    "correct_answer": "a double edge dagger"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Judges",
    "question": "what is the name of Naomi's husband?",
    "answers": "Elimelech, Abimelech, Ahimelech",
    "correct_answer": "Elimelech"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ruth",
    "question": "what are the names of Naomi's sons?",
    "answers": "Mahlon and Chilion, Mahlon and Orpah, mahlon and Samuel",
    "correct_answer": "Mahlon and Chilion"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ruth",
    "question": "what brought about the relocation of Elimelech and his family to Moab?",
    "answers": "Famine, Battle, None of the above",
    "correct_answer": "Famine"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ruth",
    "question": "Where did Elimelech died?",
    "answers": "Gath, Moab, Shiloh",
    "correct_answer": "Moab"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ruth",
    "question": "Who were the husband of Ruth and Orpah?",
    "answers": "Ahimelech and Abihu, Elimelech and Ahimelech,  Mahlon and Chilion",
    "correct_answer": "Mahlon and Chilion"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ruth",
    "question": "Why did Naomi decided to return home from Moab after she lost her husband and two sons?",
    "answers": "She heard that God has visited her people, She was tired of the place, She was sent packing",
    "correct_answer": "She heard that God has visited her people"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ruth",
    "question": "which of Naomi's daughter in law later changed her mind went back to her people?",
    "answers": "Ruth, Rehab, Orpah",
    "correct_answer": "Orpah"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ruth",
    "question": "\"... thy people shall be my people and thy God my God...\" who made this statement?",
    "answers": "Orpah, Ruth, Ruth and Orpah",
    "correct_answer": "Ruth"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ruth",
    "question": "what did Naomi asked the people to call her instead of her real name?",
    "answers": "Mother of Israel, Great woman, Mara",
    "correct_answer": "Mara"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ruth",
    "question": "what does Mara imply?",
    "answers": "Joy, bitterness, Prosperity",
    "correct_answer": "bitterness"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ruth",
    "question": "what is the name of Elimelech relation that is describe as a mighty man of wealth?",
    "answers": "Ahimelech, Boaz, none of the Above",
    "correct_answer": "Boaz"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ruth",
    "question": "the first name mentioned in 1st Samuel is ....................?",
    "answers": "Eli, Hannah, Elkanah",
    "correct_answer": "Elkanah"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st Samuel",
    "question": "what is the relationship between Peninnah and Hannah?",
    "answers": "mates in marriage, Blood sisters, Mother and daughter",
    "correct_answer": "mates in marriage"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st Samuel",
    "question": "what is the name of the place Elkanah travel with his family for a yearly sacrifice?",
    "answers": "Moab, Bethel, Shiloh",
    "correct_answer": "Shiloh"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st Samuel",
    "question": "What is the name of the High priest at Shiloh?",
    "answers": "Eli, Zadok, Aaron",
    "correct_answer": "Eli"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st Samuel",
    "question": "................... and Hophni are brothers?",
    "answers": "Samuel, Phinehas C. None of the above",
    "correct_answer": "Phinehas"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st Samuel",
    "question": "apart from Eli, one of the following was also a priest at Shiloh?",
    "answers": "Hophni,  Elkanah, Joshua",
    "correct_answer": "Hophni"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st Samuel",
    "question": "who is the father of Samuel?",
    "answers": "Elkanah, Josiah, Ahimelech",
    "correct_answer": "Josiah"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st Samuel",
    "question": "complete this statement with one of the options below \"The LORD killeth, and .............?",
    "answers": "showeth mercy,  maketh alive, none of the above",
    "correct_answer": "maketh alive"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st Samuel",
    "question": "he bringeth ................, and bringeth up?",
    "answers": "down to the grave, Up his people, the enemies down",
    "correct_answer": "down to the grave"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st Samuel",
    "question": "the sons of Eli were also described as sons of ..............?",
    "answers": "a high priest, a great God, belial",
    "correct_answer": "belial"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st Samuel",
    "question": "...they were stronger than the lion. which of these men is David referring to?",
    "answers": "Goliath and his brother, Eli and Saul, Saul and Jonathan",
    "correct_answer": "Saul and Jonathan"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2st Samuel",
    "question": "who buried King Saul?",
    "answers": "One of his Son, David, the men of Jabeshgilead",
    "correct_answer": "Saul and Jonathan"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2st Samuel",
    "question": "who is the first son of David?",
    "answers": "Absalom, Solomon, Amnon",
    "correct_answer": "Amnon"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2st Samuel",
    "question": "who did David said, he died as a tool dieth?",
    "answers": "Abner, Joab, Jonathan",
    "correct_answer": "Abner"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2st Samuel",
    "question": ".............. is the Son of Jonathan that was lame?",
    "answers": "Mephiboseth, Ada, Shimiah",
    "correct_answer": "Mephiboseth"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2st Samuel",
    "question": "how old was David when he began to reign?",
    "answers": "30 years, 18 years, 45 years",
    "correct_answer": "30 years"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2st Samuel",
    "question": "how many years did David reign?",
    "answers": "40 years, 30 years, 55 years",
    "correct_answer": "40 years"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2st Samuel",
    "question": "one of these is not the son of David?",
    "answers": "Kish, Japhia,Shobab",
    "correct_answer": "Kish"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2st Samuel",
    "question": "who brought the ark back to Israel after it was captured by the Philistines?",
    "answers": "Samuel, David, Solomon",
    "correct_answer": "David"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2st Samuel",
    "question": "\"....how are the mighty fallen\" who made this statement?",
    "answers": "Goliath B. David C. Samuel",
    "correct_answer": "David"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2st Samuel",
    "question": "Who is the young damsel that ministered to the King David when he was old?",
    "answers": "Temar, Bethsheba, Abishag",
    "correct_answer": "Abishag"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st King",
    "question": "who is the second son of David that attempted to dethrone David as King?",
    "answers": "Solomon, Kish, Adonijah",
    "correct_answer": "Adonijah"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st King",
    "question": "which of these Mighty men of David teamed up with Adonijah to dethrone David?",
    "answers": "Solomon, Prophet Nathan, Abiathar",
    "correct_answer": "Abiathar"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st King",
    "question": "according to first king 139, who anointed Solomon as King?",
    "answers": "David, Zadok, Samuel",
    "correct_answer": "Zadok"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st King",
    "question": "David instructed Solomon to Show kindness to the sons of ...................?",
    "answers": "Absalom, Barzillai, Adonijah",
    "correct_answer": "Barzillai"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st King",
    "question": "who cursed David with a grievous curse when Absalom attempted to dethrone him?",
    "answers": "Shimei, Jonathan, Prophet Nathan",
    "correct_answer": "Shimei"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st King",
    "question": "Solomon slew ................. for desiring to have Abishag as a wife?",
    "answers": "Amnon, Adonijah, Absalom",
    "correct_answer": "Adonijah"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st King",
    "question": "what is the name of the executor that King Solomon sent to eliminate Adonijah, Joab and Shimei?",
    "answers": "Benaiah, Joab, Ehud",
    "correct_answer": "Benaiah"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st King",
    "question": "what is the name of the place where King Solomon gave God a thousand burnt offering?",
    "answers": "Shiloh, Gibeon, Jerusalem",
    "correct_answer": "Gibeon"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st King",
    "question": "King Solomon got married to the daughter of One of these Kings?",
    "answers": "King of Bashan, King Susha, King Pharaoh",
    "correct_answer": "King Pharaoh"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st King",
    "question": "Which of these nations rebelled against Israel after the death of Ahab?",
    "answers": "Moab, Gibeon, Philistine",
    "correct_answer": "Moab"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2nd King",
    "question": "...He was hairy man, and girt with a girdle of leather about his loins. ...who does this described?",
    "answers": "Moses, Elijah, Aaron",
    "correct_answer": "Elijah"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2nd King",
    "question": "what group of people did Elijah command fire to consume?",
    "answers": "the captain of fifty and his men, The Egyptians, The Philistines",
    "correct_answer": "the captain of fifty and his men"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2nd King",
    "question": "One of these Kings died without having a son?",
    "answers": "King Saul, King Jonathan, King Ahaziah",
    "correct_answer": "King Ahaziah"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2nd King",
    "question": "what is the Chariot that took Elijah to heaven called?",
    "answers": "Chariot of fire, Angelic flight, Great fire",
    "correct_answer": "Chariot of fire"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2nd King",
    "question": "what fell from Elijah when he was taken to heaven?",
    "answers": "His Staff, His mantle, His Sandals",
    "correct_answer": "His mantle"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2nd King",
    "question": "what river was parted by Elijah and Elisha?",
    "answers": "River Jordan, The Red Sea, River Nile",
    "correct_answer": "River Jordan"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2nd King",
    "question": "how many men went to search for Elijah on the mountains and valleys after he was taken to heaven?",
    "answers": "50, 75, 12",
    "correct_answer": "50"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2nd King",
    "question": "Elisha was mocked by some Children in ....... city?",
    "answers": "Shiloh, Bethel, Jordan",
    "correct_answer": "Bethel"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2nd King",
    "question": "What came out of the wood to devour the children that mocked Elisha?",
    "answers": "3 big lions, 1 Lion, 2 she Bear",
    "correct_answer": "2 she Bear"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2nd King",
    "question": "How many children were devoured by the two she Bear that came out of the wood after Elisha cursed the children?",
    "answers": "48, 25, 50",
    "correct_answer": "48"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2nd King",
    "question": "Which of these names was mentioned in 1st Chronicles chapter 1 vs 1?",
    "answers": "David, Solomon, Adam",
    "correct_answer": "Adam"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st Chronicles",
    "question": "Who is the father of Shem, Ham, and Japheth?",
    "answers": "Moses, Lot, Noah",
    "correct_answer": "Noah"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st Chronicles",
    "question": "Who is the first son of Canaan?",
    "answers": "Zidon, Egypt, Amnon",
    "correct_answer": "Zidon"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st Chronicles",
    "question": "Abraham was formerly called......... ?",
    "answers": "Abram, Nahor, Terah",
    "correct_answer": "Abram"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st Chronicles",
    "question": "who is the third son of Jacob?",
    "answers": "Reuben, Levi, Benjamin",
    "correct_answer": "Levi"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st Chronicles",
    "question": "Jesse is the son of ................?",
    "answers": "David, Uriah, Obed",
    "correct_answer": "Obed"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st Chronicles",
    "question": "Which of these died without having children?",
    "answers": "Saul, Samuel, Seled",
    "correct_answer": "Seled"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st Chronicles",
    "question": "Which of these cried out to the Lord to enlarge his coast?",
    "answers": "Jabez, Joshua, Joash",
    "correct_answer": "Jabez"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st Chronicles",
    "question": "Whose birthright was given to the sons of Joseph?",
    "answers": "Judah, Reuben, Simeon",
    "correct_answer": "Reuben"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st Chronicles",
    "question": "............ prevailed above his brethren, and of him came the chief ruler?",
    "answers": "Judah, Jacob, Dan",
    "correct_answer": "Judah"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st Chronicles",
    "question": "Why did God appeared to Solomon in the dream?",
    "answers": "He killed Goliath, because he gave God a thousand burnt offerings, He prayed",
    "correct_answer": "because he gave God a thousand burnt offerings"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2nd Chronicles",
    "question": "What did Solomon made in Jerusalem that is as plenteous as stones?",
    "answers": "Wisdom, Silver and Gold, Wives",
    "correct_answer": "Silver and Gold"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2nd Chronicles",
    "question": "Which of these Kings supported King Solomon in building the temple by supplying him men and building materials?",
    "answers": "King Huram, King Rehoboam, King Asa",
    "correct_answer": "King Huram"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2nd Chronicles",
    "question": "in what year of Solomon's reign did he began to build the temple of the Lord?",
    "answers": "1st year, 4th year, 10th year",
    "correct_answer": "4th year"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2nd Chronicles",
    "question": "............ sought the presence of Solomon to hear his wisdom?",
    "answers": "Priest, Women, Kings",
    "correct_answer": "Kings"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2nd Chronicles",
    "question": "Where was King Solomon buried?",
    "answers": "Shechem, the city of David, Judah",
    "correct_answer": "the city of David"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2nd Chronicles",
    "question": "What is the name of the city where the Israelites assembled to make Rehoboam King?",
    "answers": "Jordan, Gilgal, Shechem",
    "correct_answer": "Shechem"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2nd Chronicles",
    "question": "What is the name of the King that attacked King Rehoboam and took away the treasures of the house of the Lord?",
    "answers": "King Shishak, King Nebuchadnezzar, King Jeroboam",
    "correct_answer": "King Shishak"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2nd Chronicles",
    "question": "How old was Rehoboam when he began to reign as King?",
    "answers": "12 years, 41 years, 25 years",
    "correct_answer": "41 years"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2nd Chronicles",
    "question": "How many years did Rehoboam reigned over Judah?",
    "answers": "17 years, 20 years, 45 years",
    "correct_answer": "17 years"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2nd Chronicles",
    "question": "What is the name of the King of Persia?",
    "answers": "Nebuchadnezzar, Cyrus, Daniel",
    "correct_answer": "Cyrus"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ezra",
    "question": "Ezra is the book after ................?",
    "answers": "2nd Kings, Psalms, 2nd Chronicles",
    "correct_answer": "2nd Chronicles"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ezra",
    "question": "Ezra is the book before ..................... ?",
    "answers": "Job, Esther, Nehemiah",
    "correct_answer": "Nehemiah"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ezra",
    "question": "Who became the King of Persia after Cyrus?",
    "answers": "Darius, Titus, Mordecai",
    "correct_answer": "Darius"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ezra",
    "question": "who laid the foundation of the house of the Lord at Jerusalem when King Cyrus ordered that it should be built?",
    "answers": "Ezra, Nehemiah, Sheshbazzar",
    "correct_answer": "Sheshbazzar"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ezra",
    "question": "I .............. have made a decree; let it be done with speed?",
    "answers": "Cyrus, Darius, Ahab",
    "correct_answer": "Darius"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ezra",
    "question": "Who is the father of Ezra?",
    "answers": "Seraiah, Mordecai, Nehemiah",
    "correct_answer": "Seraiah"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ezra",
    "question": "Which of these is a key player in the book of Ezra?",
    "answers": "Ezra, Esther, Job",
    "correct_answer": "Ezra"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ezra",
    "question": "what is the tregression the Israelites put away?",
    "answers": "Strange wives, Murmuring, Killing one another",
    "correct_answer": "Strange wives"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ezra",
    "question": "One of these men was a major hindrance to the building of the house of God?",
    "answers": "Darius, Cyrus, Rehum",
    "correct_answer": "Rehum"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ezra",
    "question": "Who did Nehemiah enquiry about the state of Jerusalem from, when he was at Shushan?",
    "answers": "Hanani, Ezra, The chief priest",
    "correct_answer": "Hanani"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Nehemiah",
    "question": "In their report to Nehemiah, what did Hanani said happened to the wall of Jerusalem?",
    "answers": "is broken down, it has become old, it needed to be raised higher",
    "correct_answer": "is broken down"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Nehemiah",
    "question": "What service does Nehemiah render to King artaxerxes?",
    "answers": "His gardener, His scribe, His cupbearer",
    "correct_answer": "His cupbearer"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Nehemiah",
    "question": "What did Nehemiah demanded from the King to take to the governors on the other side?",
    "answers": "a letter, a Soldier, a Servant",
    "correct_answer": "a letter"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Nehemiah",
    "question": "Who is the keeper of the king's Forest?",
    "answers": "Shimiar, Asaph, Ezra",
    "correct_answer": "Asaph"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Nehemiah",
    "question": "What book comes after Ezra?",
    "answers": "Nehemiah, Esther, Psalms",
    "correct_answer": "Nehemiah"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Nehemiah",
    "question": "What book comes before Esther?",
    "answers": "Nehemiah, Job, Psalm",
    "correct_answer": "Nehemiah"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Nehemiah",
    "question": "Who led the building of the Sheep gate?",
    "answers": "Nehemiah, Eliashib, The Chief priest",
    "correct_answer": "Eliashib"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Nehemiah",
    "question": "Which of these gates was built by the sons of Hassenaah?",
    "answers": "the fish gate, the Sheep gate, the southern gate",
    "correct_answer": "the fish gate"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Nehemiah",
    "question": "Who is the father of Nehemiah?",
    "answers": "Hachaliah, Jehoakim, Ezra",
    "correct_answer": "Hachaliah"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Nehemiah",
    "question": "Who is the queen that refuse to come at the king's commandment by his Chamberlain?",
    "answers": "Queen Sheba, Queen Vashti, Queen Esther",
    "correct_answer": "Queen Vashti"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Esther",
    "question": "according to Esther 119, who is to take Queen Vashti's place?",
    "answers": "the next to her, Her sister, Some one better than her",
    "correct_answer": "Some one better than her"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Esther",
    "question": "Who suggested that the royal estate of Queen Vashti be given to another that is better than her?",
    "answers": "the elders, the King\u2019s mum, Memucan",
    "correct_answer": "Memucan"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Esther",
    "question": "before Esther, who was the queen of Persia?",
    "answers": "Vashti, Jezebel, Orpah",
    "correct_answer": "Vashti"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Esther",
    "question": "What is the relationship between Mordecai and Esther?",
    "answers": "Father and daughter, Friends, Cousins",
    "correct_answer": "Cousins"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Esther",
    "question": "Who is the father of Mordecai?",
    "answers": "Jair, Shallum, Ahaz",
    "correct_answer": "Jair"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Esther",
    "question": "Which of these Kings took Mordecai captive?",
    "answers": "King Ahab, King Nebuchadnezzar, King Achish",
    "correct_answer": "King Nebuchadnezzar"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Esther",
    "question": "Why was Queen Vashti punished and replaced?",
    "answers": "because she disobeyed the King's order, She committed adultery, She was drunk",
    "correct_answer": "because she disobeyed the King's order"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Esther",
    "question": "Who raised Esther?",
    "answers": "Nehemiah, King Solomon, Mordecai",
    "correct_answer": "Mordecai"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Esther",
    "question": "What number of provinces did king Ahasuerus rule over?",
    "answers": "60, 127, 224",
    "correct_answer": "127"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Esther",
    "question": "How many children does Job have?",
    "answers": "5, 3, 10",
    "correct_answer": "10"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Job",
    "question": "Doth Job fear God for nought? who made this statement?",
    "answers": "Job\u2019s friend, Satan, the wife of Job",
    "correct_answer": "Satan"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Job",
    "question": "what incident led to the death of Job's Children?",
    "answers": "They died in battle, the building collapsed upon them, they were bitten by snakes",
    "correct_answer": "the building collapsed upon them"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Job",
    "question": "\"Naked came I out of my mother's womb, and naked shall I return thither\" who made this statement?",
    "answers": "Job, Job\u2019s best friend, Job\u2019s mother",
    "correct_answer": "Job"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Job",
    "question": "\"...Dost thou still retain thine integrity? curse God, and die.\" who said this?",
    "answers": "Job's wife, Job\u2019s mother, Job\u2019s friends",
    "correct_answer": "Job's wife"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Job",
    "question": "One of these was among the 3 friends of Job who came to comfort him?",
    "answers": "Ojez, Jare, Bildad",
    "correct_answer": "Bildad"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Job",
    "question": "How long did the 3 friends of Job who came to comfort him stayed with him?",
    "answers": "1 month, 7 days and nights, 3 days",
    "correct_answer": "7 days and nights"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Job",
    "question": "Job cursed the day he was ....................?",
    "answers": "betrayed, born, sick",
    "correct_answer": "born"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Job",
    "question": "Shall mortal man be more just than God? shall a man be more pure than his maker? who said this?",
    "answers": "Eliphaz, Job, Job\u2019s wife",
    "correct_answer": "Eliphaz"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Job",
    "question": "What is the name of the place Job lived?",
    "answers": "Ur, Uz, Uzah",
    "correct_answer": "Ur"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Job",
    "question": "They that hate thee shall be clothed with ...............?",
    "answers": "Sadness, Confusion, Shame",
    "correct_answer": "Shame"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Job",
    "question": "the book of Psalms has ............. chapters?",
    "answers": "70, 150, 120",
    "correct_answer": "150"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Psalms",
    "question": "Psa 21 Why do the heathen ........... and the people imagine a vain thing?",
    "answers": "Shout, cry, rage",
    "correct_answer": "rang"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Psalms",
    "question": "Psa 38 Salvation belongeth unto the .............?",
    "answers": "Sinners, Lord, Strangers",
    "correct_answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Psalms",
    "question": "Psa 54 For thou art not a God that hath pleasure in ...................?",
    "answers": "death, wars, wickedness",
    "correct_answer": "wickedness"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Psalms",
    "question": "Psa 911 ...declare among the people his ..........................?",
    "answers": "power, doings, fire",
    "correct_answer": "doings"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Psalms",
    "question": "Psa 113 If the ...................... be destroyed, what can the righteous do?",
    "answers": "House, fence, foundation",
    "correct_answer": "foundation"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Psalms",
    "question": "Psa 141 The ............... hath said in his heart, there is no God...?",
    "answers": "Wicked, fool, wise",
    "correct_answer": "fool"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Psalms",
    "question": "psalms chapter ................... has the longest verses in the bible?",
    "answers": "119, 150 C. 100",
    "correct_answer": "119"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Psalms",
    "question": "\"Even though I walk through the valley of the ............ of death,...\" ?",
    "answers": "Darkness, dried bones, shadow",
    "correct_answer": "shadow"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Psalms",
    "question": "The Lord is my shepherd, I shall not ...........?",
    "answers": "die, cry, want",
    "correct_answer": "want"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Psalms",
    "question": "One of these names appears in proverbs chapter 1 verse 1?",
    "answers": "David, Elijah, Jesus",
    "correct_answer": "David"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Proverbs",
    "question": "Complete this statement \"A wise man will hear, and will increase .....................?",
    "answers": "strength, learning, favour",
    "correct_answer": "learning"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Proverbs",
    "question": "according to Proverbs 1 vs 7, what does fools despise?",
    "answers": "Food, instruction, Mercy",
    "correct_answer": "instruction"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Proverbs",
    "question": "according to Proverbs 67, the ant does not have ..................?",
    "answers": "Ruler, big eyes, feathers",
    "correct_answer": "Ruler"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Proverbs",
    "question": "For by me thy days shall be .................., and the years of thy life shall be increased?",
    "answers": "Blessed, multiplied, none of the above",
    "correct_answer": "multiplied"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Proverbs",
    "question": "He that tilleth his land shall be .................... with bread?",
    "answers": "Satisfied, paid, a giver",
    "correct_answer": "Satisfied"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Proverbs",
    "question": "according to Proverbs 141b what does a foolish woman does to her home?",
    "answers": "destroy it,  build it, makes it childless",
    "correct_answer": "destroy"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Proverbs",
    "question": "\"A wise .............. shall have rule over a son that causeth shame?",
    "answers": "Servant, friend, neighbor",
    "correct_answer": "Servant"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Proverbs",
    "question": "according to Prv 1820 A man's ............... shall be satisfied with the fruit of his mouth?",
    "answers": "Life, belly, family",
    "correct_answer": "belly"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Proverbs",
    "question": "according to Proverbs 201, what is a mocker?",
    "answers": "a foolish wife, a foolish child, wine",
    "correct_answer": "wine"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Proverbs",
    "question": "who is referred to in Ecclesiastes 11 as the preacher?",
    "answers": "David, Solomon, Elijah",
    "correct_answer": "Solomon"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ecclesiastes",
    "question": "according to the preacher, what abides forever?",
    "answers": "heaven, The earth, man",
    "correct_answer": "The earth"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ecclesiastes",
    "question": "according to Ecclesiastes 112 who is the preacher?",
    "answers": "a priest, A King, a judge",
    "correct_answer": "A King"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ecclesiastes",
    "question": "what is said to be mad in Ecclesiastes 22?",
    "answers": "Laughter, Wine, Marriage",
    "correct_answer": "Laughter"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ecclesiastes",
    "question": "according to to Ecclesiastes 212b there was no .................. under the sun?",
    "answers": "Profit B. hiding C. favour",
    "correct_answer": "Profit"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ecclesiastes",
    "question": "to everything there is what?",
    "answers": "a purpose, A Season, reward",
    "correct_answer": "A Season"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ecclesiastes",
    "question": "according to Ecclesiastes 311, what did God made everything in its time?",
    "answers": "Beautiful, great, abundance",
    "correct_answer": "Beautiful"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ecclesiastes",
    "question": "\"The fool foldeth his hands together, and eateth his own ...............\" ?",
    "answers": "Fresh, profit, future",
    "correct_answer": "Fresh"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ecclesiastes",
    "question": "\"Two are better than one; because they have a good ................ for their labour?",
    "answers": "Comfort, Reward, focus",
    "correct_answer": "Reward"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ecclesiastes",
    "question": "\"Better is a poor and a wise child than an old and ......................... ?",
    "answers": "Foolish King, foolish woman, quarrelsome woman",
    "correct_answer": "Foolish King"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ecclesiastes",
    "question": "what are the names of the 3 kings that was mentioned in Micah 1 vs 1?",
    "answers": "Jothem, Ahaz & Hezekiah, Joash, Ahaz & Ahab, Hezekiah, Jeroboam & Rehoboam",
    "correct_answer": "Jothem, Ahaz & Hezekiah"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Micah",
    "question": "what nation does the 3 Kings mentioned in Micah 1  1 rule over?",
    "answers": "Israel, judah, Syria",
    "correct_answer": "judah"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Micah",
    "question": "\" Therefore I will make .................. as an heap of the field, \"?",
    "answers": "Samaria, Israel, Jericho",
    "correct_answer": "Samaria"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Micah",
    "question": "\" For the inhabitant of .................. waited carefully for good?",
    "answers": "Samaria, Maroth, Judah",
    "correct_answer": "Maroth"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Micah",
    "question": "the houses of .................... shall be a lie to the kings of Israel?",
    "answers": "Achzib, Zion, wicked",
    "correct_answer": "Achzib"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Micah",
    "question": "woe to them that devise what?",
    "answers": "kill their neighbors, Iniquities, oppress the poor",
    "correct_answer": "Iniquities"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Micah",
    "question": "who shall be ashamed according to Micah 37?",
    "answers": "The Seer, the king, the children of Israel",
    "correct_answer": "The Seer"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Micah",
    "question": "according to Micah 310 what was Zion build up with?",
    "answers": "Blood, clay, woods",
    "correct_answer": "Blood"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Micah",
    "question": "which of these divine for money according to Micah 311?",
    "answers": "the judge, the priest, The Prophets",
    "correct_answer": "The Prophets"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Micah",
    "question": "how many chapters does the book of Micah have?",
    "answers": "7, 4, 10",
    "correct_answer": "7"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Micah",
    "question": "how did Nahum describe God in chapter 1 vs 2?",
    "answers": "a good God, A Jealous God, a mighty God",
    "correct_answer": "A Jealous God"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Nahum",
    "question": "what does God reserve for his enemies?",
    "answers": "Fire, Wrath, curses",
    "correct_answer": "Wrath"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Nahum",
    "question": "what is referred to as the dust of God's feet?",
    "answers": "nations, the sea, The Cloud",
    "correct_answer": "The Cloud"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Nahum",
    "question": "and................... will pursue his enemies?",
    "answers": "Darkness fire, flood",
    "correct_answer": "Darkness"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Nahum",
    "question": "\".................. of the mighty is made red...\"?",
    "answers": "sword, horse, Shield",
    "correct_answer": "Shield"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Nahum",
    "question": "which of these shall be led away captive according to Nahum 2 vs 7?",
    "answers": "Huzzab, Josiah, Jeroboam",
    "correct_answer": "Huzzab"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Nahum",
    "question": "which of these nations is said to be, of old like a pool of water?",
    "answers": "Nineveh, Bethel, Jordan",
    "correct_answer": "Nineveh"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Nahum",
    "question": "\"thy nobles shall dwell in the dust.\" what nation does this refer to?",
    "answers": "the Israelites,  Assyria, the Jebusite",
    "correct_answer": "Assyria"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Nahum",
    "question": "how many chapters does the book of Nahum has?",
    "answers": "3, 5, 7",
    "correct_answer": "3"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Nahum",
    "question": "What book comes after Nahum?",
    "answers": "Nehemiah, Habakkuk, Micah",
    "correct_answer": "Habakkuk"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Nahum",
    "question": "I will stand upon my ................... ?",
    "answers": "Watch, table, cities",
    "correct_answer": "Watch"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Habakkuk",
    "question": "what did the Lord instructed Habakkuk to write?",
    "answers": "Vision, the law, the commandments",
    "correct_answer": "Vision"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Habakkuk",
    "question": ".... though it tarry, wait for it. what does this refer to?",
    "answers": "Vision, the coming of the Lord, showers of blessings",
    "correct_answer": "Vision"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Habakkuk",
    "question": "who shall live by faith?",
    "answers": "the Israelites, the soldiers, The Just",
    "correct_answer": "The Just"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Habakkuk",
    "question": "\"Woe to him that buildeth a town with ................ \"?",
    "answers": "Sinner's money, Blood, cursed money",
    "correct_answer": "Blood"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Habakkuk",
    "question": "according to Malachi 220, where is the Lord?",
    "answers": "In His Holy Temple, in heaven, in Israel",
    "correct_answer": "In His Holy Temple"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Habakkuk",
    "question": "according to hak 33, what is the earth full of?",
    "answers": "His Praise, his glory, his holiness",
    "correct_answer": "His Praise"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Habakkuk",
    "question": "which of these tents did Malachi saw in affliction?",
    "answers": "the tents of Israel, The Tents Of Cushan, the tents of Sodom",
    "correct_answer": "The Tents Of Cushan"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Habakkuk",
    "question": "according to Mal. 311, what stood still in their habitation?",
    "answers": "The Sun & The Moon, the mountains, the rivers",
    "correct_answer": "The Moon, the mountains"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Habakkuk",
    "question": "how many chapters are in the book of habakkuk?",
    "answers": "3, 6, 2",
    "correct_answer": "3"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Habakkuk",
    "question": "what is the name of Zechariah's father?",
    "answers": "Berechiah, Amos, Josedech",
    "correct_answer": "Berechiah"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Zechariah",
    "question": "how many horns did Zechariah saw in his vision?",
    "answers": "4, 10, 7",
    "correct_answer": "7"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Zechariah",
    "question": "how many Carpenters did Zechariah saw in his vision?",
    "answers": "5, 4, 10",
    "correct_answer": "10"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Zechariah",
    "question": "what kind of wall did the Lord said he will be unto Jerusalem round about?",
    "answers": "Wall Of Fire, wall of cloud, wall of wind",
    "correct_answer": "Wall Of Fire"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Zechariah",
    "question": "which of these places did the Lord asked to deliver herself?",
    "answers": "Judah, Zion, Jerusalem",
    "correct_answer": "Zion"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Zechariah",
    "question": "who did Zechariah saw Satan standing by his right hand to resist him?",
    "answers": "Joshua, Berechiah, Joash",
    "correct_answer": "Joshua"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Zechariah",
    "question": "what kind of mountain did the four chariots Zechariah saw, came out from in between?",
    "answers": "Mountain of smoke, mountain of fire, mountain of brass",
    "correct_answer": "Mountain of smoke"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Zechariah",
    "question": "which of the chariots had red horses?",
    "answers": "The First, the second, the third",
    "correct_answer": "The First"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Zechariah",
    "question": "which of these was sent unto the house of God to pray before the Lord?",
    "answers": "Sherezer, Josiah, Joshua",
    "correct_answer": "Sherezer"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Zechariah",
    "question": "according to Zechariah's prophecy, what is the name of the place that the bastard will dwell?",
    "answers": "Ashdod, Gath, Gaza",
    "correct_answer": "Ashdod"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Zechariah",
    "question": "Which of these names were mentioned in Mal. 1 2?",
    "answers": "Jacob and Esau, Cain and Abel, David and Solomon",
    "correct_answer": "Jacob and Esau"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Malachi",
    "question": "who does Malachi described as \" the people against whom the Lord hath indignation forever?",
    "answers": "Edom, Israel, Egypt",
    "correct_answer": "Edom"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Malachi",
    "question": "\"and if I be a master where is my fear?\" who made this comment?",
    "answers": "God, Prophet Malachi, David",
    "correct_answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Malachi",
    "question": "what does the priest offered on God's altar that angered him in chapter 17?",
    "answers": "Polluted Bread, sick sheep, dead goats",
    "correct_answer": "Polluted Bread"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Malachi",
    "question": "how many verses has chapter 1",
    "answers": "12, 14, 10",
    "correct_answer": "14"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Malachi",
    "question": "Chapter 2 warning is for the ____?",
    "answers": "Church, Priests, Isreal",
    "correct_answer": "Priests,"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Malachi",
    "question": "for the lips of a Priests ought to preserve ____?",
    "answers": "Wisdom, Understanding, Knowledge",
    "correct_answer": "Knowledge"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Malachi",
    "question": "How many chapter has the book of malachi?",
    "answers": "3, 4, 5",
    "correct_answer": "4"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Malachi",
    "question": "After malachi comes the?",
    "answers": "The Old Testerment, The New Testerment, Matthew",
    "correct_answer": "The New Testerment"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Malachi",
    "question": "Which Prophet was sent before the great and dreadful day of the Lord",
    "answers": "Elijah, Moses, Job",
    "correct_answer": "Elijah"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Malachi",
    "question": "which of these names did not reflect in the book of Genesis?",
    "answers": "Enoch, Ham, Elizabeth",
    "correct_answer": "Elizabeth"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Genesis",
    "question": "which of these events is not recorded in the book of Genesis?",
    "answers": "Tower of Babel, The Birth of Moses, The ark",
    "correct_answer": "The Birth of Moses"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Genesis",
    "question": "Amos was a shepherd from",
    "answers": "Uz, Tekoa, Aven",
    "correct_answer": "Tekoa"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Amos",
    "question": "Jeroboam was the son of",
    "answers": "Jehoash, Hazael, Benhaded",
    "correct_answer": "Jehoash"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Amos",
    "question": "How many Israel\u2019s Neighbor\u2019s did God pass judgment on?",
    "answers": "7, 9, 11",
    "correct_answer": "7"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Amos",
    "question": "In chapter 5v7 the sovereign Lord Almighty says \u201cThere will be ____& ____ of sorrow in the city streets\u201d?",
    "answers": "Crying & Sadness, Willing & Shouting, Wailing & Cries",
    "correct_answer": "Wailing & Cries"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Amos",
    "question": "The Lord told the people of ____, \u201cI did not demand sacrifices and offerings during those forty years?",
    "answers": "Judah, Israel, Cyrus",
    "correct_answer": "Israel"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Amos",
    "question": "According to chapter 6 v 8 who said he hate the pride of the people of Israel?",
    "answers": "The sovereign Lord Almighty, Jesus Christ, Holy Spirit",
    "correct_answer": "The sovereign Lord Almighty"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Amos",
    "question": "Chapter 5v9 says \u201cHe brings destruction on the ___ and their ___?",
    "answers": "Great and their Mighty, Biggest and their stronghold, Mighty and their Strongholds",
    "correct_answer": "Mighty and their Strongholds"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Amos",
    "question": "Can two walk together ___ there agree?",
    "answers": "Although, Unless, Expect",
    "correct_answer": "Unless"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Amos",
    "question": "The lord build his home where according to chapter 96?",
    "answers": "In heavens, On Earth, In Israel",
    "correct_answer": "In heavens"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Amos",
    "question": "The Lord says that \u201cA day is coming when I will restore the kingdom of ______\u201d?",
    "answers": "David, Solomon, Jeroboam",
    "correct_answer": "David"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Amos",
    "question": "Who appeared in the desert, baptizing and preaching?",
    "answers": "Mark, Jesus, John",
    "correct_answer": "John"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Mark",
    "question": "John clothes were made of ___?",
    "answers": "Camel\u2019s hair, sheep\u2019s hair, Snake\u2019s skin",
    "correct_answer": "Camel\u2019s hair"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Mark",
    "question": "Jesus called two fishermen in Mark Chapter one ___& ___?",
    "answers": "Simon & Andrew, Simon & John, James & Mark",
    "correct_answer": "Simon & Andrew"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Mark",
    "question": "What is the relationship between Simon & Andrew?",
    "answers": "Siblings, Brothers, Family",
    "correct_answer": "Brothers"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Mark",
    "question": "Mark chapter 3 has how many verses?",
    "answers": "35, 30, 40",
    "correct_answer": "35"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Mark",
    "question": "Jesus teach about the parable of the sower beside Lake ___?",
    "answers": "Judah, Galilee, Samaria",
    "correct_answer": "Galilee"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Mark",
    "question": "\u201cTalitha, koum\u201d means ___?",
    "answers": "Little girl, I tell you to get up\u201d, \u201cSmall Boy, I \u201ctell you to get up\u201d , \u201cSmall girl, I tell you to wake up\u201d",
    "correct_answer": "\u201cLittle girl, I tell you to get up\u201d"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Mark",
    "question": "Herods\u2019s daughter danced during whose birthday?",
    "answers": "Philistine\u2019s birthday, Herod\u2019s birthday, Pharos\u2019s birthday",
    "correct_answer": "Herod\u2019s birthday"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Mark",
    "question": "Who killed John?",
    "answers": "Herod, Pilate,  Saul",
    "correct_answer": "Herod"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Mark",
    "question": "Simon was from ___?",
    "answers": "Israel, Egypt, Cyrene",
    "correct_answer": "Cyrene"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Mark",
    "question": "Complete this verse 1v2, \u201cMay God our father and the Lord Jesus Christ give you ___ & ___?",
    "answers": "Favor & Peace, Grace & Favor, Grace & Peace",
    "correct_answer": "Grace & Peace"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ephesian",
    "question": "By birth the Gentiles are called the ___?",
    "answers": "Uncircumcised, Circumcised, Born Again",
    "correct_answer": "Uncircumcised"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ephesian",
    "question": "It is through Christ that all of us, Jews and Gentiles, are able to come in ___ Spirit into the presence of the father?",
    "answers": "Two, One, Three",
    "correct_answer": "One"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ephesian",
    "question": "Show your love by being ___ with one another?",
    "answers": "Tolerant, Caring, Good",
    "correct_answer": "Tolerant"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ephesian",
    "question": "He who gave gift appointed some to be Apostles, Prophets, Evangelists, pastors and ___?",
    "answers": "Lecturer, Teachers, Givers",
    "correct_answer": "Teachers"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ephesian",
    "question": "Since you are God\u2019s dear Children, you must try to ___?",
    "answers": "Be like Him, Be like them, Be with them",
    "correct_answer": "Be like Him"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ephesian",
    "question": "Chapter 5v22 says Wives, submit to your husbands as the ___?",
    "answers": "God, Lord, Almighty",
    "correct_answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ephesian",
    "question": "It is Children Christian duty to obey their ___?",
    "answers": "Parents, Elders, Fathers",
    "correct_answer": "Parents"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ephesian",
    "question": "The last word in the book of Ephesians is___?",
    "answers": "Amen, Grace, Love",
    "correct_answer": "Love"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ephesian",
    "question": "Chapter 6 has how many verses ___?",
    "answers": "20, 24 39",
    "correct_answer": "24"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ephesian",
    "question": "Chapter 1v5 to ___ be the ___ forever and ___ Amen?",
    "answers": "God, Glory, Ever, Jesus, Favor, Glory, God, Blessing, Ever",
    "correct_answer": "God, Glory, Ever"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Galatians",
    "question": "Who wrote the book of Galatians___?",
    "answers": "Matthew, Saul, Paul",
    "correct_answer": "Paul"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Galatians",
    "question": "May the grace of our Lord Jesus Christ be with you all, my ___&____Amen?",
    "answers": "Fathers & Mothers, Breathers & Beloved, Brother & Sister",
    "correct_answer": "Brother & Sister"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Galatians",
    "question": "How many chapters are in the book of Galatians?",
    "answers": "6, 8, 7",
    "correct_answer": "6"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Galatians",
    "question": "Which book is before the book of Galatians?",
    "answers": "2 Corinthians, Ephesians, Galatians",
    "correct_answer": "2 Corinthians"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Galatians",
    "question": "Chapter 4v7 you are no longer a slave but a ___ or ___?",
    "answers": "Breathers or Beloved, Son or Daughter, Breathers or Son",
    "correct_answer": "Son or Daughter"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Galatians",
    "question": "Chapter 2v16 says \u201cYet we know that a person is put right with God only through___?",
    "answers": "Grace, Faith, Peace",
    "correct_answer": "Faith"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Galatians",
    "question": "Chapter 2v19 says so far as the law is concerned, however I am dead, killed by the ___ itself?",
    "answers": "Law, Sin, Devil",
    "correct_answer": "Law"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Galatians",
    "question": "Abraham had two sons, one by a slave woman, the other by a ___ woman?",
    "answers": "Loss, Great, Free",
    "correct_answer": "Free"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Galatians",
    "question": "But the law has nothing to do with ___?",
    "answers": "Faith, Grace, Salvation",
    "correct_answer": "Faith"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Galatians",
    "question": "Revelation is the record of the event that is revealed by ___?",
    "answers": "Jesus Christ, God, Angles",
    "correct_answer": "Jesus Christ"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Revelation",
    "question": "To how many cities was the vision of Christ sent to ___?",
    "answers": "14, 7, 8",
    "correct_answer": "7"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Revelation",
    "question": "Who hold back the four winds so that no wind should blow on the earth or the sea or against any tree?",
    "answers": "6 Angels, 3 Angels, 4 Angels",
    "correct_answer": "4 Angels"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Revelation",
    "question": "In chapter 1v7 how many angles stand at the four corners of the earth?",
    "answers": "6, 4, 8",
    "correct_answer": "4"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Revelation",
    "question": "Which angle blew his trumpet in chapter 11?",
    "answers": "First Angels, The seventh Angel, Last Angels",
    "correct_answer": "The seventh Angel"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Revelation",
    "question": "In chapter 14 How many people were with the lamb standing on mount Zion,___?",
    "answers": "140,000people, 104,000 people, 144,000 people",
    "correct_answer": "144,000 people"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Revelation",
    "question": "In how many hour was Babylon punished___?",
    "answers": "Hours, 2 hours, 1 hour",
    "correct_answer": "Hour"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Revelation",
    "question": "May the grace of the Lord Jesus be with ___?",
    "answers": "Everyone, You, Us all",
    "correct_answer": "Everyone"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Revelation",
    "question": "Revelation 22 has how many verses?",
    "answers": "22, 23, 21",
    "correct_answer": "21"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Revelation",
    "question": "Then I saw a new ___ and a new ___?",
    "answers": "Earth and a new Pluto, Heaven and a new Earth, Mars and a new heaven",
    "correct_answer": "Heaven and a new Earth"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Revelation",
    "question": "Matthew 11-17 shows that truly?",
    "answers": "Jesus Christ was form the lineage of Abraham, Direct son of Adam, The youngest son of Joseph",
    "correct_answer": "Jesus Christ was form the lineage of Abraham"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Matthew",
    "question": "Jesus Christ was given birth to by?",
    "answers": "Hannah, Mary, Magdalene",
    "correct_answer": "Mary"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Matthew",
    "question": "Joseph divorced Mary?",
    "answers": "No, maybe, Yes",
    "correct_answer": "Yes"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Matthew",
    "question": "Matthew 121 clearly indicate the purpose of Christ Jesus coming ___?",
    "answers": "To All mankind, To All earth, To all race",
    "correct_answer": "To All mankind"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Matthew",
    "question": "How many wise men actually visited the family of Joseph at Jesus birth?",
    "answers": "3, 5, Undisclosed",
    "correct_answer": "Undisclosed"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Matthew",
    "question": "Who killed children in Israel as Herod did when Jesus was born?",
    "answers": "Pharaoh, Heroes, Herod",
    "correct_answer": "Pharaoh"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Matthew",
    "question": "When was Jesus Christ was given birth to at ___?",
    "answers": "Egypt, Bethlehem, Canaan",
    "correct_answer": "Bethlehem"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Matthew",
    "question": "According to Matthew 5v13 what did Jesus Christ makes us?",
    "answers": "Salt and light of the world,  Salt and Brightness of the world,  Salt and Seasonal of the earth.",
    "correct_answer": "Salt and light of the world"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Matthew",
    "question": "Is it true that Christian can be perfect as read in Matthew 548?",
    "answers": "Only the Jews can be perfect, yes,  No",
    "correct_answer": "Yes"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Matthew",
    "question": "Who said why are ye so fearful, o ye of little faith?",
    "answers": "Paul, Jesus Christ, God",
    "correct_answer": "Jesus Christ"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Matthew",
    "question": "Does john 13 shows that JESUS CHRIST created all things?",
    "answers": "Yes, No, Not all",
    "correct_answer": "It is good"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "John",
    "question": "Is it good we attend wedding ceremony according to John 22?",
    "answers": "It is not Good, It is kind of good, It is good",
    "correct_answer": "It is good"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "John",
    "question": "Who came to Jesus Christ by night?",
    "answers": "Necodemus, Judas, John",
    "correct_answer": "Necodemus"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "John",
    "question": "The great woman evangelist recorded in JOHN 4 Is?",
    "answers": "Woman of Samaria, Woman of Israel,  Woman of Judah",
    "correct_answer": "Woman of Samaria"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "John",
    "question": "How many basket of fragments of food was left after feeding five thousand people?",
    "answers": "12, 8, 11",
    "correct_answer": "12"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "John",
    "question": "Who said \u2018It is I, be not afraid\u201d?",
    "answers": "Jesus, Jesus Christ, The king",
    "correct_answer": "Jesus Christ"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "John",
    "question": "To whom was this said \u201cNeither do I condemn thee, go and sin no more\u201d?",
    "answers": "The Condemned robber,  The Foreign adulteress, The Samaritan",
    "correct_answer": "The Foreign adulteress"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "John",
    "question": "The pool with five porches, in Hebrew is called ____?",
    "answers": "Bethel, Bethzatha, Bethany",
    "correct_answer": "Bethzatha"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "John",
    "question": "According to John 12, how many days before the Passover did Jesus Christ went to Bethany?",
    "answers": "6 days, 7 days, 8 days",
    "correct_answer": "6 days"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "John",
    "question": "At which lake did Jesus Christ appeared to his disciples at John 21?",
    "answers": "Lake Tiberias, Lake Chad, Lake glial",
    "correct_answer": "Lake Tiberias"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "John",
    "question": "The book of Philippian was written by?",
    "answers": "John, Paul alone, Paul & Timothy",
    "correct_answer": "Paul & Timothy"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Philippian",
    "question": "Initially the book of Philippian was written to?",
    "answers": "people at Philippi, The saints, Bishops and Deacons at Philippi, The Church",
    "correct_answer": "The saints, Bishops and Deacons at Philippi"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Philippian",
    "question": "Complete this verse Philippian 19 \u201cBecause I know that by means of your ___ and the help which comes from the Spirit of Jesus Christ I shall be free\u201d?",
    "answers": "Prayers, supplications, Sacrifices",
    "correct_answer": "Prayers"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Philippian",
    "question": "Complete this verse 121 \u201cFor to me to live is ____ and to die is gain?",
    "answers": "Christ, God, Blood",
    "correct_answer": "Christ"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Philippian",
    "question": "From Philippian 215 God want us to be ___?",
    "answers": "Blameless and free, Blameless and harmless, Blameless and holy",
    "correct_answer": "Blameless and harmless"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Philippian",
    "question": "\u201cThat I have not run in vain, neither labor in vain\u201d who said it?",
    "answers": "Peter, John, Paul",
    "correct_answer": "John"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Philippian",
    "question": "In Philippian 219 who did Paul send?",
    "answers": "Timothy, Agrippa, Jude",
    "correct_answer": "Timothy"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Philippian",
    "question": "Where is this written \u201cRejoice in the Lord always again and again I say rejoice\u201d?",
    "answers": "Philippian45, Philippian48, Philippian44",
    "correct_answer": "Philippian44"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Philippian",
    "question": "Philippian213 says \u201cBecause God is always at work in you to make you ___ and ___ to obey his own purpose\u201d?",
    "answers": "willing and able, willing and ok, Compiled and able",
    "correct_answer": "willing and able"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Philippian",
    "question": "Philippian has how many chapters?",
    "answers": "Chapters, 4 Chapters, 8 Chapters",
    "correct_answer": "4 Chapters"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Philippian",
    "question": "Was Ezekiel taken with the captives?",
    "answers": "Yes, No, Not sure",
    "correct_answer": "Yes"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ezekiel",
    "question": "How many heavenly creatures that appeared to Prophet Ezekiel?",
    "answers": "4, 3, 2",
    "correct_answer": "4"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ezekiel",
    "question": "Who saw the glory of God at the river of Cheber?",
    "answers": "Paul, Ezekiel, Jesus",
    "correct_answer": "Ezekiel"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ezekiel",
    "question": "According to Ezekiel69 why did God judge the children of Israel?",
    "answers": "Their Sin, Their Hatred, Their Disobedient",
    "correct_answer": "Their Hatred"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ezekiel",
    "question": "Did God totally destroyed the sinful Israelites at the time of prophet Ezekiel according to Ezekiel68?",
    "answers": "Not fully, Yes, No",
    "correct_answer": "Not fully"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ezekiel",
    "question": "On what day of the forth month of the thirtieth year was Ezekiel living with those in exiles?",
    "answers": "Sixth, Fifth, Twenty Fifth",
    "correct_answer": "Fifth"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ezekiel",
    "question": "According to the book of Ezekiel chapter 8 evil deeds were done to the------?",
    "answers": "Temple of God, People of God, House of The Saint",
    "correct_answer": "Temple of God"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ezekiel",
    "question": "______ Come not near any man upon whom is the mark and begin at my sanctuary\u201d was addressed to whom ___?",
    "answers": "The man clothed with skin, The man clothed with linen, The man clothed with cloth",
    "correct_answer": "The man clothed with linen"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ezekiel",
    "question": "Where did Ezekiel hear the voice of the Lord in Chapter 1 v 3?",
    "answers": "Israel, Rome, Babylon",
    "correct_answer": "Babylon"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ezekiel",
    "question": "According to Ezekiel 1660 what type of covenant did God make with the returning captive?",
    "answers": "A promising covenant,  A solemn covenant, An everlasting covenant",
    "correct_answer": "An everlasting covenant"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Ezekiel",
    "question": "Habakkuk means?",
    "answers": "To Embrace, Repentance, Injustice",
    "correct_answer": "To Embrace"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Habakkuk",
    "question": "What was shown to Habakkuk?",
    "answers": "The Land, Iniquity, Law",
    "correct_answer": "Iniquity"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Habakkuk",
    "question": "Habakkuk describe the law as___?",
    "answers": "Reggie, Fierce, Slacked",
    "correct_answer": "Slacked"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Habakkuk",
    "question": "What sin did Habakkuk declare before the Lord that Judah committed?",
    "answers": "Eating meat sacrificed to idols, Eating the forbidding fruit, Eating dead animal",
    "correct_answer": "Eating meat sacrificed to idols"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Habakkuk",
    "question": "The Chaldeans are described as ____ and ___?",
    "answers": "Good and Honey Nation, Sweet and Hasty Nation, Bitter and Hasty Nation",
    "correct_answer": "Bitter and Hasty Nation"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Habakkuk",
    "question": "God said Habakkuk will not believe in the plans He has for him even if He tells him?",
    "answers": "True, false.",
    "correct_answer": "True"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Habakkuk",
    "question": "How did Habakkuk described the eyes of God?",
    "answers": "as Purer than to Behold Evil, Bright as the sun, Pure as gold",
    "correct_answer": "as Purer than to Behold Evil"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Habakkuk",
    "question": "According to Habakkuk, the just shall live by___?",
    "answers": "Grace, Faith, Love",
    "correct_answer": "Faith"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Habakkuk",
    "question": "Habakkuk's second complains was ____?",
    "answers": "Will God be silent while the wicked swallow, up people more righteous than themselves?, Will God not answer his prayers?, Will God restore the land of Judah?",
    "correct_answer": "Will God be silent while the wicked swallow up people more righteous than themselves?"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Habakkuk",
    "question": "All the earth should ___ before the Lord?",
    "answers": "Pay attention, Pray, Keep Silent.",
    "correct_answer": "Keep Silent"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Habakkuk",
    "question": "Paul told Titus, he will spend his winter in Nicopolis?",
    "answers": "True, false",
    "correct_answer": "True"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Titus",
    "question": "The grace of God that bring about salvation as appeared to ___men?",
    "answers": "Some, You, All",
    "correct_answer": "All"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Titus",
    "question": "When did God give the hope for eternal life?",
    "answers": "In the seventh Year of Titus, Before the War starts, Before The World Began",
    "correct_answer": "Before The World Bega"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Titus",
    "question": "Where was Titus left?",
    "answers": "Crete, Babylon, Cyrus",
    "correct_answer": "Crete"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Titus",
    "question": "Paul advise his readers to avoid Foolish questions?",
    "answers": "True, False",
    "correct_answer": "True"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Titus",
    "question": "What kind of doctrine did Titus preached about?",
    "answers": "Sound Doctrine, Early Doctrine, Accent Doctrine",
    "correct_answer": "Sound Doctrine"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Titus",
    "question": "According to Paul, how should we live in this world?",
    "answers": "Right, Purely and Lovely, Soberly, Righteously and Godly, Holy, Godly and Righteously",
    "correct_answer": "Soberly, Righteously and Godly"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Titus",
    "question": "The cretiens are described as ____;___ and ___?",
    "answers": "Liars, Evil Beast and Slow Bellies, Evil, wicked and lustful, Liers, lustful and Evil Beast",
    "correct_answer": "Liars, Evil Beast and Slow Bellies"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Titus",
    "question": "Titus first word was Paul?",
    "answers": "True, false",
    "correct_answer": "True"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Titus",
    "question": "As regards human government, Paul encourage Titus to tell the people to be Loyal and subjective?",
    "answers": "True, false.",
    "correct_answer": "True"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Titus",
    "question": "Colossians 11 says \u201cFrom Paul, who by God\u2019s will is an Apostle of Christ Jesus, and from our brother ____\u201d?",
    "answers": "Pitter, Timothy, Colossae",
    "correct_answer": "Timothy"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Colossians",
    "question": "The book was written to ____people?",
    "answers": "Israel, Corinth, Colossae",
    "correct_answer": "Colossae"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Colossians",
    "question": "The people learnt of God\u2019s grace from___?",
    "answers": "Timothy, Paul, Epaphras",
    "correct_answer": "Epaphras"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Colossians",
    "question": "You have been raised to life with___?",
    "answers": "Christ, The Lord, Us",
    "correct_answer": "Christ"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Colossians",
    "question": "You real life is with Christ and when He appears, then you too will ___with him?",
    "answers": "Go, Appear, Reign",
    "correct_answer": "Appear"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Colossians",
    "question": "Christ is the visible likeness of the invisible ___?",
    "answers": "King, God, Being",
    "correct_answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Colossians",
    "question": "Be persistent in prayer, and keep ____ as you pray\u2026?",
    "answers": "Alert, Praying, signing",
    "correct_answer": "Alert"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Colossians",
    "question": "You must put to ____ then, the earthly desires?",
    "answers": "Away, Sleep, Death",
    "correct_answer": "Death"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Colossians",
    "question": "The book of Colossians has how many Chapter?",
    "answers": "8, 3, 4",
    "correct_answer": "4"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Colossians",
    "question": "Be sure to finish the task you were given in the Lord Service. This was said by Paul to who?",
    "answers": "Timothy, Aechippus, Laodicea",
    "correct_answer": "Aechippus"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Colossians",
    "question": "Who wrote the book of First John?",
    "answers": "James, John, Paul",
    "correct_answer": "John"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1 John",
    "question": "The second book after first John is?",
    "answers": "Third John, Forth John, Second John",
    "correct_answer": "Third John"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1 John",
    "question": "The command John wrote in verse two was ____command?",
    "answers": "New,  old, First",
    "correct_answer": "New"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1 John",
    "question": "But if we live in light, just as he is in the _____?",
    "answers": "Dark, Bright, Light",
    "correct_answer": "Light"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1 John",
    "question": "But if we confess our sin to God, he will keep his ____?",
    "answers": "Love, Promise, Covenant",
    "correct_answer": "Promise"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1 John",
    "question": "_____ himself is the means by which our sin is forgiven?",
    "answers": "Lord, Paul, Christ",
    "correct_answer": "Christ"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1 John",
    "question": "Those who say they know Him, but do not obey his commands, are liars and there is no ____ in them?",
    "answers": "Fear, Care, Truth",
    "correct_answer": "Truth"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1 John",
    "question": "My dear friends lets love one another, because Love come from _____?",
    "answers": "God, Above, Heaven",
    "correct_answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1 John",
    "question": "Christ Command us to love___?",
    "answers": "Our self,  One another, Others",
    "correct_answer": "One another"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1 John",
    "question": "You have ___, you that believe in the Son of God?",
    "answers": "Long Life, Great Faith, Eternal Life",
    "correct_answer": "Eternal Life"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1 John",
    "question": "In the days of Daniel what is the name of the Babylonian king?",
    "answers": "Nebuchad-nez'zar, Jehoiakim, Jerobuam",
    "correct_answer": "Nebuchad-nez'zar"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Daniel",
    "question": "In Daniel 11 who was the king of Judah?",
    "answers": "Nebuchad-nez'zar, je-hoi'akim, Mishael",
    "correct_answer": "je-hoi'akim"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Daniel",
    "question": "What language were the Hebrew youths required to learn?",
    "answers": "Chaldean, Babylon, Israel",
    "correct_answer": "Chaldean"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Daniel",
    "question": "How many years were the youth to be trained before entering the king's service?",
    "answers": "Years, 5 years, 3years",
    "correct_answer": "3 years"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Daniel",
    "question": "The name Belshazzar was given to which of these Hebrew youths?",
    "answers": "Hananiah, Daniel, Mishael",
    "correct_answer": "Daniel"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Daniel",
    "question": "What kind of food did the Hebrew youths requested to be given?",
    "answers": "Fruit, Vegetables, Grain",
    "correct_answer": "Vegetables"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Daniel",
    "question": "What tribe in Israel is Daniel from?",
    "answers": "Judah, Samaria,  Lebanon",
    "correct_answer": "Judah"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Daniel",
    "question": "Why did King Nebuchadnezzar summon the wise men?",
    "answers": "To be teachers, To cook the king\u2019s meal, To interpret dreams",
    "correct_answer": "To interpret dreams"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Daniel",
    "question": "What element is the head of the image in the king's dream made of?",
    "answers": "Sliver, Gold, Clay",
    "correct_answer": "Gold"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Daniel",
    "question": "The feet and toes of the image was a mixture of what elements?",
    "answers": "Clay and Iron, Gold and Silver, Clay and Gold",
    "correct_answer": "Clay and Iron"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Daniel",
    "question": "Who was Hosea's father?",
    "answers": "Gomer, Diblaim, Be-eri",
    "correct_answer": "Be-eri"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Hosea",
    "question": "Hosea was a prophet in which country?",
    "answers": "Israel, Judah, Babylon",
    "correct_answer": "Israel"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Hosea",
    "question": "God told Hosea to go and marry a woman of.........?",
    "answers": "levy, Prostitute, Baal",
    "correct_answer": "Prostitute"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Hosea",
    "question": "What is the name of Hosea's wife?",
    "answers": "Jezreel, Jehu, Gomer",
    "correct_answer": "Jezreel"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Hosea",
    "question": "What is the meaning of the name \"Loammi\" Hosea's third child?",
    "answers": "Not my people, Cast out people, Called out people",
    "correct_answer": "Not my people"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Hosea",
    "question": "What book is before the book of Hosea?",
    "answers": "Joel, Obadiah, Daniel",
    "correct_answer": "Daniel"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Hosea",
    "question": "What book is after the book of Hosea?",
    "answers": "Obadiah, Joel, Ezekiel",
    "correct_answer": "Joel"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Hosea",
    "question": "The book of Hosea illustrates God\u2019s........?",
    "answers": "Pain and regret, Love and mercy, Love and judgment",
    "correct_answer": "Love and mercy"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Hosea",
    "question": "The marriage between Hosea and Gomer symbolizes?",
    "answers": "relationship between God and his people, relationship between Israel and Judah, relationship between God and Church",
    "correct_answer": "relationship between God and his people"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Hosea",
    "question": "What great city was Jonah sent to proclaim a message of doom?",
    "answers": "Nineveh, Amittai, Judah",
    "correct_answer": "Nineveh"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Jonah",
    "question": "Jonah ran away from God and boarded a ship to what city?",
    "answers": "Tarshish, Judah,  Amittai",
    "correct_answer": "Tarshish"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Jonah",
    "question": "Whose son was Jonah?",
    "answers": "Amittai, Jacob, Mechezedech",
    "correct_answer": "Amittai"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Jonah",
    "question": "What turbulence befell the ship going to Tarshish?",
    "answers": "A ranging cloud, A violent storm, A wild wind",
    "correct_answer": "A violent storm"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Jonah",
    "question": "After casting lots who was blamed for the calamity?",
    "answers": "Traders, Merchant, Jonah",
    "correct_answer": "Jonah"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Jonah",
    "question": "In order to calm the sea what what was done to Jonah?",
    "answers": "He was thrown into the sea, He was sent out, He was asked to pray",
    "correct_answer": "He was thrown into the sea"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Jonah",
    "question": "What kind of animal swallowed Jonah?",
    "answers": "A shake, A fish, A Doffing",
    "correct_answer": "A fish"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Jonah",
    "question": "Jonah was in the belle of the fish for how many days?",
    "answers": "days , 5 days, 3 days",
    "correct_answer": "3days"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Jonah",
    "question": "In Jonah 34, Jonah proclaimed saying in .......days Nineveh will be overthrown?",
    "answers": "Days, 30 days, 20 days",
    "correct_answer": "Days"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Jonah",
    "question": "Why did God reconsider the calamity he said he would bring on Nineveh?",
    "answers": "they repented, they died, they cried",
    "correct_answer": "they repented"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Jonah",
    "question": "Elizabeth is a wife to which of these men?",
    "answers": "John B. Paul C. Zechariah",
    "correct_answer": "Zechariah"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Luke",
    "question": "What message did the Angel deliver to Zechariah?",
    "answers": "Elizabeth will bear a child, Elizabeth will bear a son, Baby Jesus is coming",
    "correct_answer": "Elizabeth will bear a son"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Luke",
    "question": "What name is to be given to Elizabeth's unborn child?",
    "answers": "John, Joel, Gabriel",
    "correct_answer": "John"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Luke",
    "question": "What instruction was given to Zechariah regarding John?",
    "answers": "He must not eat, He must not Sleep, He must not drink wine",
    "correct_answer": "He must not drink wine"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Luke",
    "question": "What is the name of the Angel who appeared to Zechariah?",
    "answers": "Gabriel, Michael, Matthew",
    "correct_answer": "Gabriel"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Luke",
    "question": "In the account of Luke a certain virgin was promised to a man, who was that virgin?",
    "answers": "Mary, Jane, Juliet",
    "correct_answer": "Mary"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Luke",
    "question": "Greetings you highly favored one who made this statement?",
    "answers": "Angel Gabriel, John, Holy Spirit",
    "correct_answer": "Angel Gabriel"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Luke",
    "question": "Who passed a decree that all inhabitants be registered?",
    "answers": "Pharos, Roman Empire, Caesar Augustus",
    "correct_answer": "Caesar Augustus"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Luke",
    "question": "In the parable of the sower what does the seed represent?",
    "answers": "the word of God, The seed, the soil",
    "correct_answer": "the word of God"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Luke",
    "question": "Who were the two men that appeared before Jesus during his transfiguration?",
    "answers": "Mathew and Paul, James and John, Moses and Elijah",
    "correct_answer": "Moses and Elijah"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Luke",
    "question": "Who wrote the book of Romans?",
    "answers": "Paul, Saul, Peter",
    "correct_answer": "Paul"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Roman",
    "question": "Complete this statement \"For all those who sinned without law will also perish without......?",
    "answers": "Mercy, Law, Savior",
    "correct_answer": "Law"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Roman",
    "question": "To whom does Paul sends greetings referring to them as fellow workers in Christ Jesus?",
    "answers": "Mary and Aquila, Julia and Mary,  Aquila and Priscilla",
    "correct_answer": "Aquila and Priscilla"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Roman",
    "question": "According to Roman's 154, for all the things that were written beforehand were written for our...........?",
    "answers": "Instruction, Guidance, Passage",
    "correct_answer": "Instruction"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Roman",
    "question": "According to Romans who is regarded as the father of faith?",
    "answers": "Abraham, Isaac, Jacob",
    "correct_answer": "Abraham"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Roman",
    "question": "Paul\u2019s letters to the Romans was specifically addressed to?",
    "answers": "Antioch, Israel, Cling to what is good",
    "correct_answer": "Cling to what is good"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Roman",
    "question": "How many chapters are in the book of Romans?",
    "answers": "18, 16, 21",
    "correct_answer": "16"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Roman",
    "question": "What book comes after Romans?",
    "answers": "John, Acts, 1 Corinthians",
    "correct_answer": "1 Corinthians"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Roman",
    "question": "Romans 12 Vs 9 admonishes us to hate what is bad and...........?",
    "answers": "Cling to what is good, Cling to what heavenly, Cling to what is divine",
    "correct_answer": "Cling to what is good"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Roman",
    "question": "According to Romans 6 Vs 23 the wages of sin is what?",
    "answers": "Wealth, Health, Death.",
    "correct_answer": "Death"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Roman",
    "question": "Who wrote the book of second John?",
    "answers": "James, Elder,  John",
    "correct_answer": "Elder"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2 John",
    "question": "How many Chapters is in the book of second John?",
    "answers": "1, 2, 3",
    "correct_answer": "1"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2 John",
    "question": "How many verses are in the book of second John all together?",
    "answers": "13, 12, 31",
    "correct_answer": "13"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2 John",
    "question": "Verse 9 says \u201cAnyone who does not stay with the teaching of Christ, but goes beyond it, does not have___\u201d?",
    "answers": "Faith, Christ, God",
    "correct_answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2 John",
    "question": "Who said this\u201dI have so much to tell you, but I will rather not do it with paper and ink?",
    "answers": "Paul, John, Mark",
    "correct_answer": "John"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2 John",
    "question": "The book of second John was written to who?",
    "answers": "the people in John, the teachers, The dear lady and her children",
    "correct_answer": "The dear lady and her children"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2 John",
    "question": "The love I speak of means that we must live in obedience to-------- commands?",
    "answers": "king\u2019s, God\u2019s, Law\u2019s",
    "correct_answer": "God\u2019s"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2 John",
    "question": "Verse 13 says \u201cthe children of your dear ____ send you greetings?",
    "answers": "Brother, Sister, Uncle",
    "correct_answer": "Sister"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2 John",
    "question": "Verse 12 & 13 can be classified as?",
    "answers": "Truth and Love, Conclusion, Final words",
    "correct_answer": "Final"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2 John",
    "question": "Verse 7 says \u201dmany deceivers have gone out all over the _________?",
    "answers": "World, land, earth",
    "correct_answer": "World"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2 John",
    "question": "Who wrote the book of third John?",
    "answers": "James, Elder, John",
    "correct_answer": "Elder"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "3 John",
    "question": "How many Chapters is in the book of third John?",
    "answers": "1, 2, 3",
    "correct_answer": "1"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "3 John",
    "question": "How many verses are in the book of third John all together?",
    "answers": "13, 12, 15",
    "correct_answer": "15"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "3 John",
    "question": "The book of second John was written to who?",
    "answers": "Gaius, Timothy, The church",
    "correct_answer": "Gaius"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "3 John",
    "question": "Verse 4 says \u201cnothing makes me happier than to hear that my children live in the_____?",
    "answers": "Faith, Lord, Truth",
    "correct_answer": "Truth"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "3 John",
    "question": "Who did not pay attention to what the letter the elder wrote to the church?",
    "answers": "John, Paul, Diotrephes",
    "correct_answer": "Diotrephes"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "3 John",
    "question": "Verse 4 says \u201cmy dear friends do not imitate what is ____?",
    "answers": "Good, worst, Bad",
    "correct_answer": "Bad"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "3 John",
    "question": "Verse 14 & 15 can be classified as?",
    "answers": "Truth and Love, Final greetings, Final words",
    "correct_answer": "Final greetings"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "3 John",
    "question": "Who likes to be a leader?",
    "answers": "John, Gaius, Diotrephes",
    "correct_answer": "Diotrephes"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "3 John",
    "question": "For they sent out on their in the service of Christ, without accepting any help from____?",
    "answers": "Unbelievers, the church, Diotrephes",
    "correct_answer": "Unbelievers"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "3 John",
    "question": "James 11 says \u201cfrom James, a servant of ___ and of the ___?\u201d",
    "answers": "Lord, Savior, God, Lord Jesus Christ, Lord Jesus, God",
    "correct_answer": "God, Lord Jesus Christ"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "James",
    "question": "Who wrote the book of James?",
    "answers": "James, Jonah, John",
    "correct_answer": "James"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "James",
    "question": "James 19 says \u201cthose people who are poor must be glad when ___ lift them up?",
    "answers": "James, Jesus, God",
    "correct_answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "James",
    "question": "James 515 says \u201cthe prayer made in___ will heal the sick?",
    "answers": "Grace,  Faith, unity",
    "correct_answer": "Faith"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "James",
    "question": "Happy are those who remain faithful under___?",
    "answers": "Cause, Trials, Temptation",
    "correct_answer": "Trials"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "James",
    "question": "How many chapter has the book of James?",
    "answers": "Cause, Trials, Temptation",
    "correct_answer": "Trials"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "James",
    "question": "How many chapter has the book of James?",
    "answers": "3, 5, 7",
    "correct_answer": "5"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "James",
    "question": "James 57 says \u201cbe patient then, my brothers and sisters, until the ___ comes?",
    "answers": "Lord, King, James",
    "correct_answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "James",
    "question": "The last Chapter of the book of James has how man verses?",
    "answers": "10, 20, 30",
    "correct_answer": "20"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "James",
    "question": "Teachers will be judge with greater___?",
    "answers": "Anger, Mercy, Strictness",
    "correct_answer": "Strictness"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "James",
    "question": "Show me how anyone can have faith without ___?",
    "answers": "Supplication, Action, Prayer",
    "correct_answer": "Action"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "James",
    "question": "Peter was an Apostle Of___?",
    "answers": "God, James, Jesus Christ",
    "correct_answer": "Jesus Christ"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1 Peter",
    "question": "Peter wrote his first book to the people scattered throughout Pontus, Galatia, Cappadocia, Asia and ___?",
    "answers": "Bithynia, Cyprus,  Cannann",
    "correct_answer": "Bithynia"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1 Peter",
    "question": "Even Gold which can be destroyed, is tested by ___?",
    "answers": "Sulfur,  Fire, Brimstone",
    "correct_answer": "Fire"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1 Peter",
    "question": "1 peter 18 says \u201cyou love him, although you have not seen him, and you believe in him, although you did not ______?",
    "answers": "Touch him, feel him, See him",
    "correct_answer": "See him"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1 Peter",
    "question": "Rid yourself then of all ____?",
    "answers": "Lies, Evil, Bad",
    "correct_answer": "Evil"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1 Peter",
    "question": "Come to the Lord, the ______, rejected by people as worthless?",
    "answers": "Living Stone, Christ, Jesus Christ",
    "correct_answer": "Living Stone"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1 Peter",
    "question": "1 peter 26 says \u201c\u2026\u2026I chose a valuable stone, which I am placing as the ____ in Zion?",
    "answers": "Alphastone, Livingstone, Conerstone",
    "correct_answer": "Conerstone"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1 Peter",
    "question": "1 peter 57 says \u201cleave all your worries with him, because he ____ for you?",
    "answers": "Live, Care, Appeal",
    "correct_answer": "Care"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1 Peter",
    "question": "Paul regard Silas as a faithful_____?",
    "answers": "Fellow-Child, Fellow-Christian, Fellow-Friend",
    "correct_answer": "Fellow-Christian"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1 Peter",
    "question": "The whole verses in the book of 1 peter are amounted to___?",
    "answers": "109, 199, 105",
    "correct_answer": "105"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1 Peter",
    "question": "What\u2019s Peter full name?",
    "answers": "Simon Peter, Johnson Peter, Peter Packer",
    "correct_answer": "Simon Peter"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2 Peter",
    "question": "2 peter 13says \u201cGod\u2019s divine power has given us____ we need?",
    "answers": "most things, something, Every thing",
    "correct_answer": "Every thing"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2 Peter",
    "question": "2 peter 21says \u201cFalse prophets appeared in the past among the people, and in the same way False ___ will appear among you?",
    "answers": "Prophets, Teachers, Leaders",
    "correct_answer": "Teachers"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2 Peter",
    "question": "2 peter 33says \u201cFirst of all, you must understand that in this last days some people will appear whose lives are controlled by their own_____?",
    "answers": "Lust, Desire, Thought",
    "correct_answer": "Lust"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2 Peter",
    "question": "What is the last chapter of the book of 2 peter?",
    "answers": "chapter 3, chapter 4, chapter 5",
    "correct_answer": "Chapter 3"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2 Peter",
    "question": "Chapter 3 has how many chapters?",
    "answers": "44, 20, 18",
    "correct_answer": "18"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2 Peter",
    "question": "Chapter 38 says \u201cthere is no different in the Lord\u2019s sight between one day and______; to him there is no different?",
    "answers": "One year, A thousand years, Hundred years",
    "correct_answer": "A thousand Years"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2 Peter",
    "question": "A pig that has been _____, go back and roll in the mud?",
    "answers": "Washed, Rubbed, kept",
    "correct_answer": "Washed"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2 Peter",
    "question": "Which book comes after 2 peter?",
    "answers": "John, 1 John, 3 John",
    "correct_answer": "1 John"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2 Peter",
    "question": "Jude is the brother of_____?",
    "answers": "John, James, Joseph",
    "correct_answer": "James"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Jude",
    "question": "Jude was called by who?",
    "answers": "James, Jesus, God",
    "correct_answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Jude",
    "question": "The book of Jude has how many chapters?",
    "answers": "2, 3, 1",
    "correct_answer": "1"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Jude",
    "question": "What is the total number of verses in the book of Jude is___?",
    "answers": "25, 22, 20",
    "correct_answer": "25"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Jude",
    "question": "According to verse 6 who did not stay within the limits of their proper authority___?",
    "answers": "Principalities, Angels, Soldiers",
    "correct_answer": "Angels"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Jude",
    "question": "Who was the seventh direct descendent from Adam?",
    "answers": "Jesus, David, Enoch",
    "correct_answer": "Enoch"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Jude",
    "question": "According to verse 14 the Lord will come with many thousands of ____?",
    "answers": "Soldiers, Fire, Holy Angels",
    "correct_answer": "Holy Angels"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Jude",
    "question": "In the last days people will appear who will mock you, people who follow their own _____ desires?",
    "answers": "Godless, Thoughtful, faultless",
    "correct_answer": "Godless"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Jude",
    "question": "The book of Philemon was written to who?",
    "answers": "Paul, Peter, Philemon",
    "correct_answer": "Philemon"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Philemon",
    "question": "Who said this in verse 4; Brother Philemon, every time I pray, I mention you and give thanks to my God?",
    "answers": "Paul, Philemon, Peter",
    "correct_answer": "Paul"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Philemon",
    "question": "Paul was a prisoner for the sake of who?",
    "answers": "Timothy, Jesus Christ, Onesimus",
    "correct_answer": "Jesus Christ"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Philemon",
    "question": "Verse 3 says; May God our father and the lord Jesus Christ give you ___&____?",
    "answers": "Faith & Love, Grace & Peace, life and love",
    "correct_answer": "Grace & Peace"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Philemon",
    "question": "Philemon has how many Chapters?",
    "answers": "1, 2, 3",
    "correct_answer": "1"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Philemon",
    "question": "Philemon has how many verses in total",
    "answers": "25, 26, 27",
    "correct_answer": "25"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Philemon",
    "question": "I am Paul, the ____ of Christ Jesus, and at present also a prisoner for His sake?",
    "answers": "Soldier, Follower, Ambassador",
    "correct_answer": "Ambassador"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Philemon",
    "question": "Paul made a request on behalf of who in verse 10?",
    "answers": "Timothy, Onesimus, Philemon",
    "correct_answer": "Onesimus"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Philemon",
    "question": "Verse 12 says; I am sending him back to you now, and with him goes my ____?",
    "answers": "Faith, Heart, Love",
    "correct_answer": "Heart"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Philemon",
    "question": "Paul kept Onesimus with him in prison for what sake?",
    "answers": "The Gospel sake, Christ sake, Philemon sake",
    "correct_answer": "The Gospel sake"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Philemon",
    "question": "In This Last Days God Spoke To Us through His _____?",
    "answers": "Prophet, Son, Children",
    "correct_answer": "Son"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Hebrew",
    "question": "In the past, God spoke to our ancestors many times and in many ways through the ___?",
    "answers": "Prophet, Son, Children",
    "correct_answer": "Prophet"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Hebrew",
    "question": "Who did God chose to possess all things at the end?",
    "answers": "His Son, Wisdom,  Angles",
    "correct_answer": "His son"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Hebrew",
    "question": "According to chapter 14 who was made greater than the angles?",
    "answers": "The Prophet, The Angels, The son",
    "correct_answer": "The Son"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Hebrew",
    "question": "Chapter 19 says; you love what is right and hate what is____?",
    "answers": "Bad, wrong, great",
    "correct_answer": "Wrong"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Hebrew",
    "question": "Which Apostle replaced Judas?",
    "answers": "Mathew, Matthias, Andrew",
    "correct_answer": "Matthias"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Acts",
    "question": "At what age did Moses leaved the palace of Pharaoh to visit his people in Egypt?",
    "answers": "35 years, 48 years, 40 years",
    "correct_answer": "40 years"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Acts",
    "question": "How long were the Israelites in bondage in Egypt?",
    "answers": "400 years, 550 years, 450 years",
    "correct_answer": "400 Years"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Acts",
    "question": "Where was Jacob buried?",
    "answers": "Shechem, Egypt, Edom",
    "correct_answer": "Shechem"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Acts",
    "question": "Which Apostle healed the sick with his handkerchief?",
    "answers": "Peter, Paul, John",
    "correct_answer": "Paul"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "Acts",
    "question": "Where were the disciples of Jesus first call Christians?",
    "answers": "Antioch, Nazareth, Rome",
    "correct_answer": "Antioch"
  },
  {
    "question": "which among the Disciples of Jesus Christ said this, now the end of the Commandment is charity out of a pure heart and of a good conscience, and of faith unfeigned?",
    "answers": "John the Baptist, John the beloved, Paul",
    "correct_answer": "Paul",
    "book_of_bible": "1st timothy"
  },
  {
    "question": "which is correct among these in the scripture above for there is one God, and one Mediator between God and men, which is the man -------?",
    "answers": "Moses, Peter, Christ Jesus",
    "correct_answer": "Christ Jesus",
    "book_of_bible": "1st timothy"
  },
  {
    "question": "complete the given scripture with the correct_answer this is a true saying, if a man desire the office of a bishop he desired a good?",
    "answers": "life, work, home",
    "correct_answer": "work",
    "book_of_bible": "1 timothy"
  },
  {
    "question": "which of these speaks expressively that in the latter times some shall depart from the faith?",
    "answers": "man, church, spirit",
    "correct_answer": "spirit",
    "book_of_bible": "1st timothy"
  },
  {
    "question": "which verse of the bible talks about teaching otherwise and not consenting to wholesome words?",
    "answers": "1 timothy 6: 3, 1timothy 6: 1, 1 timothy 6: 6",
    "correct_answer": "1 timothy 6:3",
    "book_of_bible": "1 timothy"
  },
  {
    "question": "which verse of the bible, \u2018was this scripture quoted, \u2019but Godliness with contentment is great gain?",
    "answers": "1 kings 6:6, 1 samuel6v:6, 1 timothy6:6",
    "correct_answer": "1 timothy 6:6",
    "book_of_bible": "1 timothy"
  },
  {
    "question": "who is this scripture referring to \u2018not given to wine, no striker, not greedy of filthy lucre; but patient, not a brawler, not covetous?",
    "answers": "priest, bishop, husband",
    "correct_answer": "bishop",
    "book_of_bible": "1 timothy"
  },
  {
    "question": "which of the following option is correct according to this scripture \u2018Unto --------- my own son in the faith; grace, mercy, and peace, from God our father and Jesus Christ our lord?",
    "answers": "Matthew, Paul, timothy",
    "correct_answer": "timothy",
    "book_of_bible": "1 timothy"
  },
  {
    "question": "complete this verse in the bible, let the woman learn in silence with all--------?",
    "answers": "sincerity, passion, subjection",
    "correct_answer": "subjection",
    "book_of_bible": "1 timothy"
  },
  {
    "question": "which of the disciples made this statement, now unto the king eternal, immortal, invisible, the only wise God, be honour and glory for ever and ever amen?",
    "answers": "john the Baptist, Paul, Matthew",
    "correct_answer": "Paul",
    "book_of_bible": "1 timothy"
  },
  {
    "question": "who in the bible made this statement and about who but, when he was in Rome, he sought me out very diligently and found me?",
    "answers": "Paul and about Caesar, Paul about Aristarchus, Paul about Onesiphorus",
    "correct_answer": "Paul about Onesiphorus",
    "book_of_bible": "2nd timothy"
  },
  {
    "question": "fill in this with the correct_answer of the disciple name only Luke is with me take -----and bring him with thee; for he is profitable to me for the ministry?",
    "answers": "Paul, Matthew, Mark",
    "correct_answer": "Mark",
    "book_of_bible": "2nd timothy"
  },
  {
    "question": "which is the name of timothy mother and grandmother?",
    "answers": "Aquila and Priscilla, Lois and Eunice, Lois and Elizabeth",
    "correct_answer": "Lois and Eunice",
    "book_of_bible": "2nd timothy"
  },
  {
    "question": "when I call to remembrance the unfeigned faith that is in thee, which dwelt first in thy grandmother Lois and thy mother Eunice; and I am persuaded that in thee also? Who made this statement and to who",
    "book_of_bible": "2 timothy",
    "answers": "Paul to timothy, Paul to Barnabas, Paul to john the Baptist",
    "correct_answer": "Paul to timothy"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2nd timothy",
    "question": "which of this verse is true?",
    "answers": "the husbandman that laboureth must be first partaker of the fruits, the husbandman that laboureth must be the first partaker of the food, the husbandman that laboureth must be the first partaker of the meat.",
    "correct_answer": "the husbandman that laboureth must be the first partaker of the fruits"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2nd timothy",
    "question": "which chapter of the bible was this quoted\u201d Study to show thyself approved unto God, a workman that needeth not to be ashamed, rightly dividing the word of truth?",
    "answers": "2nd timothy 2: 5,2nd timothy 2: 10,2nd timothy 2: 15",
    "correct_answer": "2nd timothy 2:15"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2nd timothy",
    "question": "which book of the bible recorded this \u201cThis know also, that in the last days perilous times shall come?",
    "answers": "2nd timothy 3: 1, 2nd timothy 6: 1, 2nd timothy9:1",
    "correct_answer": "2nd timothy3: 1"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2nd timothy",
    "question": "which book of the bible recorded this I have fought a good fight, I have finished my course, I have kept the faith?",
    "answers": "2nd timothy 4: 6, 2nd timothy 4: 7, 2nd timothy 4: 8",
    "correct_answer": "2nd timothy 4: 7"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2nd timothy",
    "question": "fill in the correct_answer------- the coppersmith did me much evil; the lord reward him according to his works?",
    "answers": "Erastus, Gaius, alexander",
    "correct_answer": "alexander"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2nd timothy",
    "question": "which of the disciples made this statement For I am now ready to be offered, and the time of my departure is at hand?",
    "answers": "Peter, John the Baptist, Paul",
    "correct_answer": "Paul"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2nd timothy",
    "question": "which of   these women in reference to the church in Asia was apostle Paul referring to?",
    "answers": "Lois and Eunice, Joanna and Susannah, Aquila and Priscilla",
    "correct_answer": "Aquila and Priscilla"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1 Corinthians",
    "question": "what does these actually mean, now concerning spiritual gifts, brethren I would not have you ignorant?",
    "answers": "in the dark, without understanding, lonely",
    "correct_answer": "without understanding"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st Corinthians",
    "question": "which is the names of the disciples that Paul baptized?",
    "answers": "John the Baptist and john the beloved, Aristarchus and oneisphorus, Crispus and Gaius",
    "correct_answer": "Crispus and Gaius"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st Corinthians",
    "question": "which book of the bible said this, for it is written, I will destroy the wisdom of the wise, and will bring to nothing the understanding of the prudent?",
    "answers": "1st Corinthians 1vs 6, 1st Corinthians 1vs 8, 1st Corinthians 1vs 19",
    "correct_answer": "1st corinthians1vs 19"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st Corinthians",
    "question": "which among the disciples made this statement And I was with you in weakness, and in fear, and in much trembling?",
    "answers": "Peter, James, Paul",
    "correct_answer": "Paul"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st Corinthians",
    "question": "which book of the bible is this found that your faith should not stand in the wisdom of men, but in the power of God?",
    "answers": "1st Corinthians 2vs 4, 1st peter2vs 4, 1st corinthians2vs 5",
    "correct_answer": "1st Corinthians 2vs 5"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st Corinthians",
    "question": "according to 1 Corinthians 3vs16, where does Paul imply that the temple of God was located?",
    "answers": "in the little town of Bethlehem, in heaven itself, within the physical bodies of believers",
    "correct_answer": "within the physical bodies of believers"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st Corinthians",
    "question": "which of the gifts of the holy spirit did Paul imply in 1 Corinthians 14: 1,was superior to the rest?",
    "answers": "the ability to prophesy, speaking in tongues, applying the gift of knowledge",
    "correct_answer": "the ability to prophesy"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st Corinthians",
    "question": "who or what did Paul say could not inherit the kingdom of God in 1 Corinthians 15:50",
    "answers": "Animal, Angels, flesh and blood",
    "correct_answer": "flesh and blood"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st Corinthians",
    "question": "which of this event is correct according to the book of the bible, Paul scolded the member of the church at Corinth for their flippant attitude concerning what church observance?",
    "answers": "partaking of the Lord\u2019s Supper, ordination of bishop and deacon, sharing of prayer blankets",
    "correct_answer": "partaking of the lord supper"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st Corinthians",
    "question": "which of this gift did Paul mentioned that were available to the church?",
    "answers": "Joy, Peace, Word of knowledge",
    "correct_answer": "Word of knowledge"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st Corinthians",
    "question": "which book of the bible was this recorded Therefore if any man be in Christ, he is  a new creature, old things are passed away; behold, all things are become?",
    "answers": "2 Corinthians 7vs 8, 2 Corinthians 5vs 17, 2 Corinthians5vs 17",
    "correct_answer": "2 Corinthians 5vs17"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2nd Corinthians",
    "question": "which of the following best expresses the view that most scholars hold about 2 Corinthians?",
    "answers": "it should be included in the Old Testament, it contains messages in secret code, it is composed of fragments from more than one letter",
    "correct_answer": "it is composed of fragments from more than one letter"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2nd Corinthians",
    "question": "with whom according to chapter6,should the Corinthians avoid being yoked?",
    "answers": "Romans collaborators, devils, unbelievers",
    "correct_answer": "unbelievers"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2nd Corinthians",
    "question": "which of these were Paul reason for not visiting the church at Corinth",
    "answers": "he was sick, he was in prison, he was at Rome",
    "correct_answer": "he was in prison"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2nd Corinthians",
    "question": "which chapter of the book of the bible was this recorded For our light affliction, which is but a moment, worketh for us a far more exceeding and eternal weight of glory?",
    "answers": "2 Corinthians 4vs 15, 2 Corinthians 4vs 16, 2 Corinthians 4vs 17",
    "correct_answer": "2 Corinthians 4vs 17"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2nd Corinthians",
    "question": "which chapter of the bible talks about not receiving the grace of God in vain?",
    "answers": "2 Corinthians 6vs 1, 2 Corinthians 6vs 2, 2 Corinthians 6vs 3",
    "correct_answer": "2 Corinthians 6vs1"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2nd Corinthians",
    "question": "which one of the disciples was speaking in this scripture \u201cO ye Corinthians, our mouth is open unto you, our heart is enlarged?",
    "answers": "John the Baptist, Peter, Apostle Paul",
    "correct_answer": "Apostle Paul"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2nd Corinthians",
    "question": "which verse of the bible was this recorded, \u201cBut this I say, he which Sows sparingly shall reap also sparingly; and he which Sows bountifully shall reap also bountifully?",
    "answers": "2 Corinthians 9vs 4, 2 Corinthians 9vs5, 2 Corinthians 9vs 6",
    "correct_answer": "2 Corinthians 9vs 6"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2nd Corinthians",
    "question": "complete the following chapter of the bible, Thanks be unto God for his unspeakable ----?",
    "answers": "love, grace, gift",
    "correct_answer": "gift"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2nd Corinthians",
    "question": "complete the following scripture of the bible; But he that  glorieth, let him glory in the ----?",
    "answers": "Men, Lord, Grace",
    "correct_answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "2nd Corinthians",
    "question": "which names of disciples were mentioned in respect to the church in Thessalonians",
    "answers": "Paul ,Silvanus , Timotheus,  Gaius, Onesiphorus, Aristarchus, Peter, John, Luke",
    "correct_answer": "Paul Silvanus  Timotheus"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st Thessalonians",
    "question": "according to the scripture, Paul is writing to the Christian community in Thessalonica, of which roman province was Thessalonica the province?",
    "answers": "Asia, Achaea, Macedonia",
    "correct_answer": "Macedonia"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st Thessalonians",
    "question": "what is the first word in the King James Version of 1 Thessalonians?",
    "answers": "Timotheus   Paul   Silvanus",
    "correct_answer": "Paul"
  },
  {
    "book_of_bible": "1st Thessalonians",
    "question": "According to Apostle Paul during his visits to Thessalonica he was with two others which are ------ and ------",
    "correct_answer": "Silas and timothy",
    "answers": "Silvanus and Timotheus , Gaius and timothy ,Silas and timothy"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Silas and timothy",
    "book_of_bible": "1st   Thessalonians",
    "question": "According to the book of the bible in I Thessalonians   apostle Paul wrote some letters ,where was apostle Paul when he wrote these letters?",
    "answers": "Macedonia, Rome, Corinth"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Corinth",
    "book_of_bible": "1st Thessalonians",
    "question": "who did   Paul   said   was raised from the dead?",
    "answers": "Lazarus,  Jesus, peter"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Jesus",
    "book_of_bible": "1st Thessalonians",
    "question": "According to 1 thessalonians2:5 who does Paul say is their witness?",
    "answers": "Jesus, Angels, God"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "God",
    "book_of_bible": "1st   Thessalonians",
    "question": "According to 1 Thessalonians 2:2, where had Paul been giving rough treatment and grossly insulted",
    "answers": "Macedonia, Corinth, Phillipi"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Phillipi",
    "book_of_bible": "1st   Thessalonians",
    "question": "who did   Paul said   hindered them from going to Thessalonica sooner",
    "answers": "God, Satan,   angels"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Satan",
    "book_of_bible": "1st Thessalonians",
    "question": "According to   1 Thessalonica 2:17   who or what has prevented Paul from returning to visit the Thessalonians??",
    "answers": "man,   Satan,   God"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Satan",
    "book_of_bible": "1st Thessalonians",
    "question": "According to 1 Thessalonians 3:1-2 whom did Paul send back to Thessalonica?",
    "answers": "Silas timothy Silvanus"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Timothy",
    "book_of_bible": "1st Thessalonians",
    "question": "how man chapters is in the Book of Isaiah?",
    "answers": "66, 44, 24"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "66",
    "book_of_bible": "Isaiah",
    "question": "According Isaiah1:2 hear oh heavens and give___",
    "answers": "Eyes, Supplication, Ear"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Ear",
    "book_of_bible": "Isaiah",
    "question": "which cities where mentioned in the book of Isaiah?",
    "answers": "Sodom & Gomorrah, Sodom & Rome, Egypt & Gomorrah"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Sodom & Gomorrah",
    "book_of_bible": "Isaiah",
    "question": "According Isaiah 60:8 who are these that fly as a ___ and as the ___ to their windows?",
    "answers": "Doves & Bird, Cloud & Winds, Cloud & Doves"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Cloud & Doves",
    "book_of_bible": "Isaiah",
    "question": "who is the father of Isaiah?",
    "answers": "Amoz, Aaron, Amos"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Amoz",
    "book_of_bible": "Isaiah",
    "question": "Isaiah 2:6 says \u201co house of Jacob, come ye and let us walk in the ____ of the Lord?",
    "answers": "Light, Grace, Speed"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Light",
    "book_of_bible": "Isaiah",
    "question": "Isaiah 60 has how many verses?",
    "answers": "23, 22, 30"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "22",
    "book_of_bible": "Isaiah",
    "question": "Isaiah 60:1 says Arise, shine for thy____ is come and the ____of the Lord is risen upon thee?",
    "answers": "Light & Glory, Light & Cloud, Blessing & Peace"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Light & Glory",
    "book_of_bible": "Isaiah",
    "question": "Isaiah 60:22 says A little on shall become a _____ and a small one a ________ nation?",
    "answers": "Thousand and Strong, Hundred and soft, Million and Rough"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Thousand and Strong",
    "book_of_bible": "Isaiah",
    "question": "which book is after the book of Isaiah?",
    "answers": "Ezekiel, Jeremiah, Lamentation"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Jeremiah",
    "book_of_bible": "Isaiah",
    "question": "how many chapters has the book of Jeremiah?",
    "answers": "52, 33, 100"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "52",
    "book_of_bible": "Jeremiah",
    "question": "who is the father of Jeremiah?",
    "answers": "Aaron, Hilkiah, Judah"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Hilkiah",
    "book_of_bible": "Jeremiah",
    "question": "Jehoiakim is the son of ___?",
    "answers": "Josiah, Isaiah, Zedekiah"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Josiah",
    "book_of_bible": "Jeremiah",
    "question": "who is the son of Josiah?",
    "answers": "Zedekiah, Zachariah, Zephaniah"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Zedekiah",
    "book_of_bible": "Jeremiah",
    "question": "According to Jeremiah 4:15 says\u201d for a voice declare from ___ and publish affliction from mount Ephraim?",
    "answers": "Gad, Dan, Israel"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Dan",
    "book_of_bible": "Jeremiah",
    "question": "Jeremiah 4:27 says\u201d for thus hath the Lord said, the whole land shall be ____;yet will I not make a full end",
    "answers": "Black, Waste, Desolate"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Desolate",
    "book_of_bible": "Jeremiah",
    "question": "___ book comes before Jeremiah?",
    "answers": "Isaiah, Esther, Obadiah"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Isaiah",
    "book_of_bible": "Jeremiah",
    "question": "____ book come after Jeremiah?",
    "answers": "Lamentation, Isaiah, Revelations"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Lamentation",
    "book_of_bible": "Jeremiah",
    "question": "according to Jeremiah 10:17\u201d gather up thy ___ out of the land, O inhabitant of the fortress?",
    "answers": "Wares, Loins, Space"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Wares",
    "book_of_bible": "Jeremiah",
    "question": "Jeremiah chapter 40, has how many verses?",
    "answers": "20, 30, 16"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "16",
    "book_of_bible": "Jeremiah",
    "question": "___ had a vision in Obadiah 1:1?",
    "answers": "Obadiah, Amos, Aaron"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Obadiah",
    "book_of_bible": "Obadiah",
    "question": "in Obadiah 1:1 the Lord talk about ____?",
    "answers": "Edom, Eden, Ephraim"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Edom",
    "book_of_bible": "Obadiah",
    "question": "According to Obadiah 1:1 an ____ was sent among the heathen..?",
    "answers": "Ape, Ambassador, Apple"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Ambassador",
    "book_of_bible": "Obadiah",
    "question": "Obadiah has how many verses in total?",
    "answers": "21, 20, 22"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "21",
    "book_of_bible": "Obadiah",
    "question": "Obadiah has how many chapters in total?",
    "answers": "1, 44, 9"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "1",
    "book_of_bible": "Obadiah",
    "question": "according to Obadiah 1:20\u201dand the _____ of the captivity of this host of the children of Israel shall possess that of the ____?",
    "answers": "Canaanites, Ephraim, Gilead"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Canaanites",
    "book_of_bible": "Obadiah",
    "question": "according to Obadiah 1:21\u201d and saviors shall come up on mount ___ to judge the mount of Esau and the kingdom shall be the Lords\u201d?",
    "answers": "Sinai, Zion, Esau"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Zion",
    "book_of_bible": "Obadiah",
    "question": "Behold I have made thee small among the ___ thou art greatly despised?",
    "answers": "heathen, hidden, Eaten"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "heathen",
    "book_of_bible": "Obadiah",
    "question": "Obadiah 1:17\u201dbut upon mount Zion shall be deliverance, and there shall be ___...?",
    "answers": "Grace, Peace, Holiness"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Holiness",
    "book_of_bible": "Obadiah",
    "question": "According to Obadiah 1:18\u201d and the house of Jacob shall be a___ and the house of Joseph a _?",
    "answers": "Fire & Flame, Flame & Oil, Fire & Water"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Fire & Flame",
    "book_of_bible": "Obadiah",
    "question": "The book of Joel has how many chapters??",
    "answers": "1, 2, 3"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "3",
    "book_of_bible": "Joel",
    "question": "Joel is the son of ___ ?",
    "answers": "Petheul, Peniel, Paul"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Petheul",
    "book_of_bible": "Joel",
    "question": "The book of Joel has how many chapters in total ??",
    "answers": "70, 73, 76"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "73",
    "book_of_bible": "Joel",
    "question": "The word of _____ came to Joel,according to joel 1:1?",
    "answers": "The Lord, The angels, Petheul"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "The  lord",
    "book_of_bible": "Joel",
    "question": "Awake ye drunkards, and weep and howl, all ye drinkers of wine, because of  the new wine; for it is cut off from your __?",
    "answers": "mouth, skin, wine"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "mouth",
    "book_of_bible": "Joel",
    "question": "Joel 3:1 says for behold, in those days, and in that time, when I shall bring again the captivity of ___ and Jerusalem",
    "answers": "Etophia, Judah, Cyprus"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Judah",
    "book_of_bible": "Joel",
    "question": "the sun and the moon shall be___ and the stars withdraw their___?",
    "answers": "Darkened & Shinning, Darkened & Brightness, Darkened & Glory"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Darkened & Shinning",
    "book_of_bible": "Joel",
    "question": "how many verses has the last chapter of Joel?",
    "answers": "22, 21, 20"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "21",
    "book_of_bible": "Joel",
    "question": "Joel 2:15 says blow the ___ in Zion\u2026.?",
    "answers": "Trumpet, horn, sound"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Trumpet",
    "book_of_bible": "Joel",
    "question": "Joel 3:20 says\u201d But Judah shall dwell forever, and Jerusalem from generation to__?",
    "answers": "Generation, Ever, Seeds"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Generation",
    "book_of_bible": "Joel",
    "question": "how many chapters has the book of Lamentation?",
    "answers": "5, 6, 7"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "5",
    "book_of_bible": "Lamentation",
    "question": "Judah is gone into captivity because of ____?",
    "answers": "Affliction, Sin, Stubbornness"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Affliction",
    "book_of_bible": "Lamentation",
    "question": "According to Lamentation 1:4 Zion mourn because none come to the solemn____?",
    "answers": "Break, Feasts, Wash"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Feasts",
    "book_of_bible": "Lamentation",
    "question": "Lamentation 3:8 says Also when I cry and shout, he shutteth out my ____?",
    "answers": "Self, Prayer, Peace"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Prayer",
    "book_of_bible": "Lamentation",
    "question": "I am the man that hath seen affliction by the rod of his____?",
    "answers": "Wrath, Mercy, face"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Wrath",
    "book_of_bible": "Lamentation",
    "question": "which book is before Lamentation?",
    "answers": "Jeremiah, Job, Hosea"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Jeremiah",
    "book_of_bible": "Lamentation",
    "question": "which book is after Lamentation?",
    "answers": "Ezekiel, Jeremiah, Job"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Ezekiel",
    "book_of_bible": "Lamentation",
    "question": "Lamentation 5:2 says our inheritance is turned to ___ our houses ____?",
    "answers": "Strangers & Aliens, Aliens & Space, Strangers & Space"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Strangers & Aliens",
    "book_of_bible": "Lamentation",
    "question": "According to Lamentation 5:17 for this our heart is faint, for this things our eyes are ____?",
    "answers": "Dim, Low, Doll"
  },
  {
    "correct_answer": "Dim",
    "book_of_bible": "Lamentation",
    "question": "Lamentation 5:19 says thou O Lord, remainest forever, thy throne from generation to ___?",
    "answers": "Eternity, Generation, Everlasting"
  }
]